<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-badminton</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1886-04-04/ed-1/?sp=12&amp;q=badminton</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>men and women of Xew
          York society are stiil and formal in their
          Manners would have been somewhat sur
          prised at the ciowdot vonng peoplt who
          gathered before 1 O*deek feeteVdajf after
          noon to play bidminton in a «|iucr little
          Fourth avenue buildinK- Nobody wn v,.|,.
          (us for an instant, and chaff seeniol to Ik
          tbeorderof the hour. Over in one corner
          sat four maids as upricht as dolls
          and as solemn as East [pitta fakirs.
          The? conversed in low tones and seemed
          utterly oblivious to the tfume. .So d;d
          mot of the others for that matter, and it
          didn't take a voiy shrewd observer to dis
          cover that bandminton. as played" in New
          York, consists ni conversation*; to a very
          large extent. Interspersed with a few cur
          sor, bits of hit and mi-play with the
          racquets. There were no chaperones at all
          at this RUM, and it amounted to a merry
          tort ot frolic Cor two hours bj the middle
          of the day. li wm MMuing to Hstento
          the talk, tor the Kugiish accent, which bj
          affeoted so laboriously by some of the so
          ciety people, m picked an and dropped
          pieci-«'ly as fancy dictated by the gor
          geously attired people who made badmin
          ton an excuse lor Betting without
          being oppressed by the pres
          ence of chaperone dnenneti Hut just
          let me show \ou how superior bolles are to
          beans when it comes to sightliness at play.
          Tbe biggest swell of the dandies arrived an
          hour before time. He was a small man
          w ith prominent teeth, rather a pallid face,
          and a pah* ol shadowy side whiskers. He
          penneed up to the door of the liiuisy frame
          structure, and nodded carelessly to a stolid
          Englishman who stood by the d«»or with a
          straw in his mouth and his hands in his
          pm fcete.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85047239/1886-10-13/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=badminton</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>People wlio lnmglno tlmt tlio young men
          and women of Now York society tiro still
          mul formal In tholr manners would have
          been somewhat surprised at tlio crowd of
          young pcoplo who met together ono
          nftornoon to play badminton In a queer
          little Fourth avenue building
          It didnt take a very shrowd obsorvcr
          to discover that badminton as played In
          Now York consists of conversation to a
          very largo extent Interspersed with n fow
          cursory bits of hit nnd rclsplay with tho
          racquets Tlicro wore no chnperones at
          nil at this gamo nnd it amounted to a
          merry sort of a frolic for two hours In tho
          middle of tho day It was amusing to
          listen to the talk for tho English accent
          which Is affected so laboriously by soino
          of tho aocloty people was picked up nnd
          dropped precisely as fancy dictated by tho
          gorgeously attired pooplo who made bad
          minton an excuse for meeting without
          being oppressed by tho presence of chnpur
          one duennas</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1890-03-09/ed-1/?sp=18&amp;q=badminton</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>PLAYERS OF BADMINTON. JWO CLUBS WHER1- THE WRDS" ILV VEB THE NETS. A DESCRIfTION Of
          THE GAJfE-IT- POPTJIiAltlTT AS A I.KNTl-V AMUSEMI \T *a pkople wi llesown is The pame of
          badminton, "f nli games "t akill. is pcrhaps loast kti .wa by iho publle i.t large. It is
          ncarly as mueh a game "i egilitj and quick ncss as iciinis, and, altho igb the Mercite
          required is not Tlolent, thecnjoymenl experlenced i.y tbe playcrs in a cloaely oontested
          game la Jui kcen as m tho more wldely known -istor game. lat nn Indlfferenl player
          badminton i- much the r.etter form nt sp-'M. and iho women w o go io lor it are mdre
          entbuBlaatic iu it* supporl than the most eonfirmed playcra -.i tennia The liko it becauae
          it givea them an nppetite. and iu this it nevei f.ii!-*. Cocktalla ire i t. to I c com
          jiaicl with H- Sherry and bitters hecomes na aotbing, nnd ;i good dinnei preceded bj
          badniin tBadminton may be played either -'i the lawn
          or ladoors. ln Ita Indoor fonn it is. and is likely
          to renniin. Sew-York'a fashionable L??nten paatime
          aml n- auch ii certainly deservcs praise.
          'Ih.' game aa now played i-- nol ..t greal i??
          tlquity, oi il ll la, there ia no deflnlte reoord of
          the lni't, lt ia "I Anglo-Indlan origln, and baa
          been siii.o 1E. i u favorite with -.ngllab oJheera i"
          India. The form ol game played ln Sew-York
          ri..es not diffei materlallj fr..m thal played bj
          tho Aiiin.ilai'i'l Badminton Club In India. and the
          rulA* now adopted ure pructically tlie -ainc
          Tho BBaterlala for badminton aro differcnl
          iboee uaed for tei igb the gai
          mlghl appeai simil r n e net la from two feel
          to two feel si_ ii cl es in bre idth, ai I ln_t
          N-i.'i- sei upon tlu ng poles
          nnd ia 1 ung al a distam c ol from Hve i"
          j et to six fe 1 from tbe surfa. e oi Ihe court.
          Inste i-l ol balls, sli ittlecocka, or bir la," oa they
          nrc teehnlcally c lled, are used. Tlie racq cts
          nr b it* with which l aboul are
          rencrally ol a Lighter weighl and souiewli kl smaller
          than the ordinory tennis i icque.,
          tennla ruc] et can be For in
          door pl ig a i ird" wei ;1 i incc is
          iiaed, bul oui or?, un ac. wind, i ce
          weighliLg. an ounce and three-eeTered with rubber to prevenl uu urj from nio__t
          urc, is I'
            .-fi-.
            Vl_vr' Cil's OF THE "BIRDS In dreaa ry for pla-
          ii Iminlon. Tbe exei bi*. nol lent. tennla Hannels cuu l*e and even U nnis shoes re d. lf
          ln\v aro woi feli aoles should bc ctiosen. Women should wear lo"s- t sligl tly
          .liortcr tharj the invc tional aa i
          af aome aofl Bes tuaterial thal will nol Intei
          fciv wll ii.
          l s of the court musl be Ln a
          tneas ;rc delermlned by the lize ol the Boor oi
          la\\;i npon to lie 1 dd out. Oue1 w
          elghl Uil ki i md twenty feel broad
          but the ed by the
          N xx- ork I
          nn elevatl :i i Iee1 it answers thi
          is as geod aa ui I 11 iu.ir .--i
          aat carefully with chalk lines, oi lf _
          Mr::,. i and I.
          Frn::i one to i ir peraona play n a aiie, and
          t!.e ahuttlee. k or bird^ niuM in
          Beturaed on a "volley" or before lo
          court Burface. The "blrds" are sei ed and re
          t i
          cepi that if the shuttlecock falla to the eourl
          gorface it ia ni 1 a nii__ to I plnyei
          laila to return il and lo bia aiile. Tbe servicc is
          from t!. "i c ia, 1 lie
          pl;iV,T bi fe within u section
          ?i i two i.-i t und sx, ineliea from the
          earaer. Th* divisiona "f the eourt* nr.- onlj oh
          Berve.l on the aerve, aml the playera can Btand
          wliere tliey pleae on tbeir own si ;' ft?i it
          Tlie Bhuttk I ser ed a tlu lt falla
          Wlthln the lines i I cn ice c url as in teiuiia,
          0n,l ele r of tlu c! ropea and poata I tlie et
          it touelied in tbe gervice and the "I'nd" falla
          ovor. the Btroke ia ealled a, "lot" and docs not
          connt -.r- ki er.
          Iii p|ay, b wi vi i tbe touchintj ol the :i-i by the
          glitiitlri tt g ea over counta aa a o -1
          ati"..' II the i ichi I I tlie racqui
          nel with
          tbeir racqueta, tlie st
          JVo i..nli'.' p U hand out," and in all
          ?birdB" lallin- upon boundary linea re re
          ?arded as "faulta," both iu acrvice and in play.
          fifteen point* eonatitnte the game. No over
          liain! -i:. ia all iwcd "ii the eervice. ln ja-l_
          Ing wbether pl yei I re i ied over the net,
          it is ajwi noticcd il the bird" ia st: ick be
          lote ii haa eroaaed Ihe nel aml merel been foi
          lowcl over by the raequel f player. Iu this eaae il li i t ud stroke, bul il the racquet
          itsolt tou il ea the nei tbe pl ia cotinti i a miss The game ol b dmini u introdu ed In
          thia country .luiin. the xx.i.t.-r 1-1- b I'.y ar.l t larke aad E. Langiton Wilks, and ihe
          nu eleua ot the Im New-York liudunniou Club w_? then formed. THE OEEST OF THE CI.l'B. The
          Badminton Clah was 1I10 pioneer. nnd its luoeess has iicn much greatei than Ife Ciarke aad
          Wll** dared h-iix- when they in1r duced the pamo and began to Interesl othera ln lt. The
          menilK-ishii) in 187*. was forty, and tho flret gamos wcic played in the aruioiy buildin*.
          nt Thii'iv-'iftl. st. and Broadway. Intereai m the game eteadily Increased, and the
          memberablp crew until 1884, when il numbered 100. Tbe lub then disbanded, and in I tner*
          was no playing. In I8S- ibe elub was i/,-il with seventy-flve memtiers, thal nu mber hcing
          the limit. The club waa governed ?y eommittee until 18.7. when n was tbougiu au visable to
          i and an executive eommit? tee This waa done. tbe membership Umil waa ,hMt,,;,,', veiimi,
          ization haa had a regular club e-.v.-m W en the 71si Reg.?nt nioved to _?*?? Fort\
          ftfth-ftl and Broadwa n n.oved with lt, aml th en- by game I itional facilities for
          succe__.uUy playing i w game. TIII. gCBNE AT '1 Hi- 0 '1 T.T-. Every Saturday afternoon
          tt.e blg drill room presenta a decldedly gay appearance. Men and wo.. usually t. the
          number ol 160, are there in faultless aftemoon drcaa, and the ..ir is full ol coiored
          shuttlecocka. Nine courta are lUd precUion by Jamea Kennedy. the ener eetic armorcr. and
          leiwcen gamea tea, aandwichea rved t" the metnbers and thetr visii lhal uiwrl lhe neto
          serve liaunl pennanta ol red and gold, iii. Ilrilliant guidona mark n,iei-e, t i, i- i.t
          courl h .undanea and ndd to general lieauty ol the scene. ihe c!i b h alw iys cen "f
          markcu Tbirteen of tbe twenty men ?t the ittee m lhe t'entennial s. rviees in old u P
          n.enii,.-!- "i tbe Ha Innnton h.i. nol ii name in the lb?t ol niembers not ni or less
          known to readei. ol Uie fashionable intelligence</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn97065075/1891-06-19/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=badminton</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>A GAME FOR ALL SEASONS.
          It Is Called "liadiulnton" ud Cuuie From
          England.
          Badminton was invented, or origin
          ated, whichever you please, in England,
          but owes its present rules to the Ah
          medabad Badminton club of India,
          Which has practically revived the sport.
          It is a modification of lawn tennis, with
          some important differences, as will be
          seen further on, and has the advantage
          that it can be, and generally is, played
          in-doors. This make3 it both a suramet
          and winter game.
          Tho dimensions of the court must be
          decided in a great measure by the capa
          bilities of the room in which the game
          is played. Tho best size Is one twenty
          eight feet long by twenty feet broad.
          The courts should bo marked off by
          means of pegs and strings, or better,
          when possible, by white chalk lines oe
          the floor, and divided in the following
          way: At each end ol the ground are
          two courts, ten feet square, while the
          center is formed by a piece of neutral
          ground eight feet broad by twenty feet
          long. On each of these outer lines of
          the neutral ground and in the center
          are placed tho posts which support tho
          net The net, which is two feet to two
          feet six inches deep, is suspended at a
          height of six feet from the ground, and
          firmly held by guy ropes attached to
          posts.
          The racquets used in Badminton, to
          be easily and quickly Wielded, should
          be lighter than those used in lawn ten
          nis, and consequently smaller. A shut
          tlecock is used instead of a ball, and
          may be large or small, according to tho
          wish of the players.
          In its general line, Badminton is a
          game played in the same fashion as
          lawn tennis, with tho exception that
          from one to four persons may play on a
          side, and that tho shuttlecock must be
          returned on the volley. Tho shuttle
          cock is served and returned under tho
          same provisions, except that, of course,
          if the shuttlecock falls on the ground,
          it Is counted as a miss to the player
          missing it, and to his side. The servico
          shall be from the "service-corner," tho
          server and receiver each standing with
          both feet within their respective quad
          rants until the shuttlecock is struck.
          The divisions of the respective courts
          are only observed in the serve or first
          hit; after that, the partners may stand
          where they please, on their side of tha
          net The shuttlecock must be served
          in such a way that it falls clear over the
          net, without touching the net, ropes or
          posts, and falls inside the lines of the
          service-court If the net Is touched in
          service and tho shuttlecock falls over,
          the stroke is considered as a "let," and
          does not count as a fault against the
          person serving. In play, however, the
          touching of the net by the shuttlecock,
          when it falls over, is counted as good
          stroke. If the net is touched by the
          racquets of the players, or if they reach
          over the net with their racquets, tho
          stroke counts against them. Two faults
          puts "hand out" In all cases a shuttle
          Cock falling on any of the boundary
          lines Is regarded as a fault, as if it had
          fallen outside Of the boundary lines,
          both in service and play.
          Iifteen points constitute the game.
          In service no overhand stroke is allow
          ed. The shuttlecock is judged by where
          it strikes and not by where it lies after
          striking. In judging whether a player
          has reached over tho net, the umpire
          should bo careful to note if the shuttle
          cock Is struck before it has crossed the
          net and not by the racquet of the play
          or, which is naturally carried forward
          by the impetus of the stroke and which
          might arrive at a slight angle over the
          net, although the shuttlecock itself was
          struck on the correct side. If, however,
          the net is touched by the racquet the
          stroke counts against the player, wheth
          er the shuttlecock was struck on the
          right side of the net or not
          As will be seen from the description,
          Badminton requires agility and a quick
          eye, rather than great strength, and it
          will be found to be a game at which
          girls can play with pleasure and profit
          Golden Days.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045604/1891-05-31/ed-1/?sp=9&amp;q=badminton</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>IrHE NET AND RACKET. badminton Has Not Driven Tennis From Favor. BOSSIP OF THE
          CHAMPIONS. I y Mabel Cahill, the John L. Sullivan •f the Xew York Club, and Other i Great
          Flayers. 1 i jriw YORK. May 25.—[Special Corre jpoodence.J—The tennis season of 1891 has
          fairly begun, and from present appear ances it will be the liveliest one that has aver
          been known in this country. There was a prospect earlier in the season that badminton
          might supplant the older game in favor, but every one concerned now scouts the possibility
          of such a result. No one, naturally, takes a keener interest in the question than the
          makers of tennis goods, and they report the largest advance tale* on record. It is one of
          the not to be forgotten consequences of the popularity of lawn tennis that the manufacture
          and nleof neta, rackets, lawn markers, shoes and uniforms has become a great industry. It
          is only a few years since all these goods were imported from England, the home of fee
          game; now they are practically all Bade here, and th» business amounts to something like
          $10,000,000 a year to the trade. This is looking at the other side of the sport, but the
          point of view is not an unimportant one. The clubs in and about New York are in nnmfctr
          almost legion, and they are pre paring busily for championship events, mcticaliy the
          season begins with Decora tion day, the month of fine weather before that date being given
          np to practice play ing. Of course, play begins earlier South. The Washington City
          tournament for the championship of the Southern states was held in the middle of May.
          Tomorrow the New York Tennis Club will hold its spring games, and from now to the end of
          the season in October there will be a tournament every day—for not a summer hotel of any
          size is without its tennis courts, the smaJlest villages have their clubs, and matches and
          return matches t are shrewdly relied upon to keep up the interest in the game. Undoubtedly
          the success of tennis is OLLIE CA MPBELL. largely due to the fact that men and women can
          play it together. For flirta tion purposes it may not quite eoual the sedate and sluggish
          game of croquet, but for a judicious combination of sport and opportunities for
          tete-a-tetes its equal has never been invented. Indeed, tennis is the ideal ladies' game.
          As it requires agility rather than strength to play tennis, there is no reason why women
          should not play quite as well as men, if it were not for the perpetual haudi cap ot
          skirts. As it is, an active young woman is about a match for a stout and middle-aped man,
          with equal practice, and some of the lest women players can hold their own with any but
          the very best men. i his is a test not to be recommended,how ever, as the practice of
          playing with one of the other sex rather tends to break a man up. as he is divided between
          his gallantry and his desire to excel. Thus it may easily happen that a man will show tip
          in better form at the end of a season with compara tively little practice with men than if
          he had considerable careless playing with women. Championship games are, of course, always
          between players of the •tne sex. •Since Scars, of Boston, who was an ex fi.rdinary tennis
          player, met with a dis cing accident, the honors of the game Jwe rested with the Brooklyn
          players Henry \V. Stocum, jr., son of General ll! W. Slocum, the champion of iw, and Oli
          "Ollie" Campbell, the present bolder ot the championship, both having park in past years,
          though Mr. Slocum is ;IOR a member of P:. George's Club, of New York. There is perhaps no
          place in the country where bet ter provision is made for tennis playing on large scale
          than at Prospect park, and there are few days in spring or summer when a considerable
          number of games are lot going on there simultaneously. The frequency of va ant lots in the
          resU yace sections of Brooklyn rather favors KINKY W. STOCFM. *R information of small
          neighborhood clubs, Asocial amusement rather than tine **y the result. Jill!! orlt Vf 3
          the younc woman f«g l f rather expected to win chief chain- honors this summer. This is
          Mabel K. Oahiil, of the Net York lennis Club. Miss Cahill is an woman ami won lame in the
          old nir\ at tennis tournaments before com lhl* Bhe is a vigorous, aihletic younp woman,
          with merry, iaugh yes, ana quick, vi« -rous movements. It4mlv r^ Sen 10 ,^r woman's cham-
          I P**nn P h 3 K Will not withom t n l her s:s! amp i° nfhll for oubks. Miss
          VA probabiy play in double# wiU\
          SIXTEEN PAGES.
          Miw Ballantine, of the New York club.
          Miss Robinson, of Staten Island,
          Mrs Morgan, of Short Hill*. N. J.,
          the Misses Kiting. Frazer and Temple, of
          Westchester county, and Miss Colby, of
          Orange, N. J., are among the famous play
          ers who may contert for the honors with
          Miss ah:i ! and the Roosevelt sisters. Of
          course, there will be dark horses, too, who
          at the last moment mav appear to wrest
          the leadership away from the well-known
          plavers. It is always more difficult to
          predict women's piaying than men' s.
          They have more time for practice, they
          are quite as numerous, if not more so. and
          they are far less likely to enter champion
          ship contests than men, even if quite pro
          ficient. Thus local pride may almost at
          any time force to the front some splendid
          player before unheard of outside of her
          county. It is the peculiarity of the plav
          ers of both sexes that they are at their
          best while quite young and do jiotlong
          retain their supremacy.
          Badminton came to the front last winter
          as an indoors game, for which it was well
          adapted by the smallness of the court re
          quired. A tennis court is 78 feet by 27
          wider than an ordinary city lot and nearly
          as deep. The badminton court is only 44
          feet by 20, and can be recommended for a
          home game where spare is verv limited.
          The net is shorter and higher. The short
          service line is 6 feet 6 inches from the net.
          The base line is 15 feet t inches farther
          back on either side. The net itself is 16 feet long and 5 feet high in the middle. In the
          play a shuttlecock is used in stead of the white ball used in ten nis. This is made of
          rubber and feathered to steady its (light. Ordinary tennis rackets are used instead of the
          ola faehioned "battledores." The game is, in fact, a sort of cross between lawn tennis and
          the older game, and is said to be the invention of an English officer in India, who found
          the climate too hot for ten nis. Perhaps that is the reason why old tennis players call
          badminton a lazy peo- Sle's When such sturdy at hletes as [amihon Cary and .Stanley
          Mortimer and such clever tennis experts as Miss Annie Webb, Miss Turnure, Miss Minturn and
          Miss Elsie Mitchell play and enjoy thgame, however, it can safely he assumed that, there
          is plenty of exercise in it. The rules of badminton are so simple that they can be
          summarized in a para graph. There is no authoritative Ameri can body like the National
          Tennis Associ ation, but the English rules are used: The sides toss for choiceof ends or
          service before the first game of a match, and change to the other sideof the netafter each
          game. The single-handed and double-handed game consists of fifteen ares. At "13 all," the
          side which first reaches thirteen has the option of "setting^'five; at 14 all, of setting
          three. In three-handed or four- handed jrames the game consists of twenty one aces. First
          set is at 19 all; second at 20 all. A fault made by a player whose I side is in puts a
          baud out; if made by a j player whose side is out it counts an afe to i the in side. It is
          a fault if the service is I "overhand"; if the rirs-t part of the path of the shuttlecock
          is inclined downward ;if the service falls into the wrong court; if the ser vice falls
          short of the service line or outside the bounding line; unless both the server's teet are
          in his own court; if the shuttle cock falls outside the bounds of the court; if the
          shuttlecock does not pass between the posts, or if it pass under or through tiie net or
          touch anything except the bat of the striker, or the top of the net if the shuttlecock !e
          hit twice intentionally by tiie same player; if the shuttlecock be struck before it
          crosses the striker's side of i the net; if the striker touch the net or its supports with
          his racket or otherwise, i The player in the right-hand court com mencea the game by
          serving to the plaver in the adverse right-hand oourt; if tfiat leaver return the
          shuttlecock, it must be hit ack by the in side and then returned by the out side till a
          fault is made by one j side or the other. The game is continued in this manner, count
          being chanced after j each ace ;s made. The service lines nre disregarded alter the serve
          is returned, j Iho innings always begin with the player j in the right-hand court, and
          serves arc i made alternately from each court into the one d. t.; iia.lv opposite. In two.
          three and tour-handed games, the side begin ning a game has only one hand in its nrst
          innings if there are two a side, and only two hands if there are three a side. Inatwo h
          and el game only the ptrson served to may take a serve; not so in a three or four handed
          game. The service must not begin till the opponent is ready, but any attempt to return is
          taken to indicate readiness. Any unforseen or accidental hindrance may be given by a "let"
          bv the umpire on appeal from either side "before the next service commences or before the
          players have changed sides at the end of a game. A "let" cannot be claimed it" an attempt
          I ha* been made to strike the shuttlecock Pitiably the next winter there will be a
          badminton association iu this country r or the new game may he taken under the l
          government of the tennis association. Magistrate (severely^—Why 'id drive through the
          crowded thu fhfarea at the rate of t:!teen miles an htur? Io you tlunk that the streets
          belong o you? Culprit (earnestly protesting -B_it,yg(Ur honor, 1 drm a beer wagon. PLAN
          OF A BADMINTON OOt'P.T. A GAME OF BADMINTON</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1891-10-04/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=badminton</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1907-11-10/ed-1/?sp=45&amp;q=Badminton</id>
        <rel>GAME OF BADMINTON
          I Copyright by James Elver son
          ITTS^~ ADAITNTON was invented,' or orig
          |J Ij inatcd, whichever you please, in
          I !*•"*_ England, but owes its present rules
          RtjlSSSfj to the Ahmedabad Badminton Club,
          Mvlfilr" o f India, which has practically re
          vived the sport. It is a modification
          of lawn tennis, with some important differ
          ences, as will be seen further on, and has the
          advantage that it can be,- and generally is,
          played indoors. This makes it both a sum
          mer and winter game.
          The dimensions of the court Imuit be de
          cided in a grjfat measure by the j capabilities
          of the room in, which the game lis played.
          The best size ii one 28 feet long- by 20 feet
          broad. The courts should be marked off by
          means of pegs and strings, 'or better, when,
          possible, by white chalk lines jon j the floor,
          and divided in the following way: At each
          end of the ground axe two courts. L jlO feet
          square, while the centre is formed by a piece
          of neutral ground 8 feet broad by 20 feet long.
          On each of the outer lines of the neutral
          I ground and in the centre are placed the posts
          which support the net. .C-
          The net, which is 2 feet to 2l2 l feet 6 inches
          deep, is suspended at a height of 6 feet from
          the ground, and firmly held by. guy ropes at
          i tached to posts. ,y L
          1 The racquets used in Badminton, to be easily
          and quickly wielded, should be lighter than
          those used in lawn tennis, and consequently
          smaller. A shuttlecock is used instead of a
          ball, and may be large or small, accorum" to
          the 'wish of the players. .7 .1
          In its general; line, Badminton is a game
          played in the same fashion': as lawn tenni*,
          with the exception that from one to four
          persons may play on a side, and that the shut
          tlecock must be returned on the volley. -_•
          The shuttlecock is served and returned
          under the same provisions, except that, of
          i course if the shuttlecock falls on the ground,
          it is counted as a miss to. the player missing
          it and to his side." The service shall be from
          the "service-corner," the server I and receiver
          each standing with both feet within their
          respective quadrants until the shuttlecock v
          struck.
          The divisions of the respective courts are
          only observed in the serve or first hit; after
          that the partners may 1 stand where they
          please, on their side of the ¦net....
          The shuttlecock must be served in Mich a
          wav that it falls clear over the net. without
          touching the net, ropes or posts, and falls in
          ide the lines of the service court.
          If the net is touched m service and the
          shuttlecock falls over, the stroke is oonsid
          i BOYS AND GIRLS MAGAZINE SECTION
          At tltc first tfelfOi 'crawAe6r J fyr/ff£ Jttf/a /37ered 38 a "let," and does not
          count us a fault
          against tbe person serving.
          In play, however, the touching of the net
          by the shuttlecock, when it falls over, is
          counted as good stroke.
          If the net is touched by the racquets of the
          players, or if they reach over the ne£_ with
          their racquets, the stroke counts against
          them.
          Two faultf puts "hand out." In all cases
          a shuttlecock falling on any of the boundary
          lines is regarded as a fault, as if it had fallen
          outside of the boundary lines, both in service
          and play.
          Fifteen points constitute the game. In ser
          vice no overhand stroke is allowed.
          The shuttlecock is judged by where it strikes
          and not by where it lies after striking.
          In judging whether a player has reached
          ever the net, the umpire should be careful to
          note if the shuttlecock is struck before it
          has crossed the net and not by the racquet of
          the player, which is naturally carried forward
          by the impetus of the stroke and which might
          arrive at a slight angle over the net. although
          the -shuttlecock itself was struck fairly on the
          correct side.
          If, however, the net is touched by the
          racquet the stroke counts against the player,
          whether the shuttlecock was struck on the
          right side of the net or not.
          As will be st%n from the description, Bad
          minton requires agility and a quick eye, rather
          than great strength, and it will be found to
          be a game at which girls can play with pleas
          ure and profit.</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1909-05-23/ed-1/?sp=29&amp;q=badminton</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1920-03-28/ed-1/?sp=23&amp;q=badminton</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Will Boom Badminton
          j The Badminton Club, of New York,
          an organization established in 1878,
          I which has continuously since that time
          I tried to foster and develop the game of
          I badminton in this city, will hold 07;
          I Saturday, March 27, an intercity tour?
          nament with Caines Badminton Club.
          I of Boston. There will be four matches
          of men's singles, three women's sin-j
          gles, two men's doubles, one women's
          doubles and three mixed doubles.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075189/1957-05-24/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=when+was+badminton+invented</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn97065075/1891-06-19/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=when+was+badminton+invented</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Badminton was invented, or origin
          ated, whichever you please, in England,
          but owes its present rules to the Ah
          medabad Badminton club of India,
          Which has practically revived the sport.
          It is a modification of lawn tennis, with
          some important differences, as will be
          seen further on, and has the advantage
          that it can be, and generally is, played
          in-doors. This make3 it both a suramet
          and winter game.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82006551/1941-05-29/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=when+was+badminton+invented</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1937-06-04/ed-1/?sp=10&amp;q=when+was+badminton+invented</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Authorities give 1856 as the year when
          croquet was introduced into England, and
          1873 for badminton. Both of these, came
          to the United 8tates from that country.
          It is probable, of course, that they have
          a much longer history, in some form or
          modification.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1951-05-11/ed-1/?sp=50&amp;q=when+was+badminton+invented</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84036001/1885-04-11/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=when+was+badminton+invented</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-eiffel-tower</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025121/1889-04-02/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+France+French+Paris+Worlds+Fair</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THE EIFFEL TOWER
          A Msht and Sensation for lisitor to
          1arls
          In view of the assurance of a
          creditable representation of Hawaii
          both in productions and person
          agesat the Universal Exhibition of
          this year in Paris a few facts rela
          tive to the EiffeUower culled from
          a late English paper may be of local
          interest
          The tower is named after its pro
          jector Mr Eiffel now President of
          the French Association of Engineers
          He is famed in part -for the design
          ing of a great bridge at Bordeaux
          Although the Eiffel tower was orig
          inally the conception mainly of an
          ambition likened to that of Ameri
          cans by the English paper referred
          to for having the highest structure
          in the world it was also early as
          sumed that it would have uses in the
          interest of science It is claimed
          and anticipated that it will be very
          raluable for observatory purposes
          owing to the perfect clearness of the
          air at its summit
          The tower is to be one thousand
          feet in height At the date of the
          description here drawn upon it had
          attained an altitude of 738 feet or
          162 feet higher than any other build
          ing on earth There were 180 men
          employed then in its construction
          100 preparing the lifts at the base
          and 80 riveting the perfectly fitted
          parts at top To avoid fatiguing the
          workmen aloft in descending several
          times a day for food a restaurant is
          fitted up at a height of about 400
          feet There are to bo four perman
          ent restaurants for the refreshment
          of visitors on the first stage of the
          tower
          A spiral stairway runs from the
          ground to the summit of the tower
          but it is believed that few if any in
          experienced heads will be able to en
          dure the strain of going round and
          round or looking down from the
          giddy heights Therefore there are
          to be mechanical lifts to the top
          four to the first stage two to the
          second and thence one to the sum
          mit the crown of observation The
          final lift will have a capacity of 65
          persons I1 ares will be 6 francs to
          the first stage and 5 francs to the
          top to be reduced on Sundays to 1
          franc and 3 francs respectively No
          visitors are allowed during construc
          tion except on Sundays owing to
          danger of accident from a hammer
          or bolt falling from aloft Mr iffol
          pays a weekly visit to thoworks The
          workmeu have to endure severe cold
          at the summit whore the thermome
          ter sometimes registers several de
          grees below zero
          The panoramic view to be obtained
          of the beautiful city of Paris and
          environs froin the top of the Eiffel
          tower must be loft to the readers
          imagination until assisted by ac
          counts from the Hawaiian Commis
          sioners Col Spalding and Hon J
          A Cummins or unofficial visitors
          from these isies or descriptive writ
          ers in the foreign press after ex
          periencing the sensations of the
          sublime ascension and prospect</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn91068084/1889-04-26/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+Paris+Exhibition+1000+Feet+High+France+French+Worlds+Fair</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>NEARLY 1000 FEET HIG
          The Great Eiffel Tower at the
          Paris Exposition.
          How the Colossal Structure, Just
          Completed, was Erected.
          The great Eiffel tower at the Paris Exhi
          bition has just been completed, and a de
          scription of the colossal structure, with an
          account of the way it was built, and a sketch
          of its constructor, will bo appropriate at this
          time. It is scarcely necessary to say that the
          U
          mm
          Cologne
          Cathedral,
          511 ft.
          The Eiffel Tower,
          9S4 ft. The Great
          Pyramid,
          480 ft.
          Eiffel tower is by far the highest structure in
          the world. It presents a decidedly unique ap
          pearance, too in general outline not unlike a
          stack of four gigantic muskets with their
          butts well and solidly spread and their bay
          onets joining at their tips.
          The Eiffel tower stands in the Champ de
          Mars, almost on the left bank of the river
          Seine, just in the rear of the Quai d'Orsay,
          and in fact a part of its foundation is sunk
          through an old arm of the river, which lias
          been filled in these many years. Its base
          covers a plot of ground 328 feet square, or
          nearly two and a half acres in extent.
          GUSTAVF. EIFFEL.
          It Ls really at the base a group of four tow
          ers, each nearly fifty feet square, placed at
          the corners of the plot of ground, and in
          clining toward each other as they rise at an
          angle of fifty-four degrees. Each tower con
          sists of four columns, bound together by
          trusswork, and each column rests on a
          masonry pier which is so built that the weight
          of the column rests upon it squarely and not
          at an ancle.
          As the tower is 0S4 feet high. it will be
          seen that the matter of providing a solid
          foundation was one of great importance.
          There was a lot of boring and digging befon
          the spot upon which the tower stands was
          finally selected.
          The foundation rests upon a thick stratum
          of sand and gravel. It may be well to say.
          for the benefit of those who think sand is a
          rather treacherous sort f ground, that a bed
          of sand and gravel, away under ground, is
          pretty solid stuff. One of the towers of the
          Brooklyn Bridge rests on that sort of base.
          The foundations of the two piers of the Eiffel
          tower farthest from the Seine rest on sand
          and gravel about twenty-five feet below the
          surface of the ground. These foundations
          were laid in open excavations, and consist
          first of great solid platforms of beton, six
          feet thick, and next of four stone piers which
          rise to the surface to receive the iron col
          umns. The foundations for the two piers nearest
          the river were not so easily laid. It was
          necessary to go thirty-five feet below the
          surface of the ground, end this was sixteen
          feet under water. So caissons had to be
          used, as they were in building the Brooklyn
          Bridge piers.
          A caisson is in effect simply an enormous
          iron box, without any cover, turned upside
          down. The method of using it is to dig the
          earth out from under it and allow it to
          gradually settle as the excavation pro
          gresses, meanwhile building the pier on top.
          When the required depth is reached the cais
          a .n itself is filled up with the beton, and it
          forms the bottom layer of it a foundation.
          A shaft is left running through the pier
          auove for entrance and exit as the work goes
          on, and the air in the caisson and shaft is
          compressed to whatever is necessary to keep
          the water out of the bottom. It is the prin
          ciple of the diving bell modified.
          Work on the foundations was begun on
          January 28, 1887, and at the end of June they
          were completed. Then began the labor of
          setting up the innumerable pieces of iron of
          which the tower is composed, and it went on
          at a vapid rate, for each individual piece
          came from the works of M. Eiffel, at Leval-lois-Pere
          cut to its exact dimensions, fitted
          and drilled, so that no modification was neces
          sary at the place of operations. Up to a
          height of about fifty feet the workmen re
          quired no scaffolding to work upon, as each
          pier supported itself, although each leaned
          toward the others. Then an artificial support
          had to le provided, as above that height, un
          til the first platform was reached, the center
          of gravity of each pier would fall outside of
          the base.
          And so piece by piece the towers grew,
          and at length reached a height of 140 feet.
          Then four enormous horizontal trusses were
          put in place to connect the four piers. These
          were nearly 140 feet long and weighed a
          good many tons, and hi order to place them
          in position it was necessary to erect an ex
          tensive false work, or scaffolding. "When
          these trusses were in position, and the con
          necting beams to form a flooring were in
          place, the workmen ha1 a great solid plat
          form, nearly 15U feet above the ground and
          upward of 1 oJ feet square, to work upon.
          These four inclined piers and the four big
          connecting trusses form the solid groundwork
          of the tower. There is nothing particularly
          unique in the detail of construction. The
          work is simply a system of trusses and braces,
          in which the material is so placwd as to make
          a strong and light structure. The four great
          arches which rise between the piers, imme
          diately under the great horizontal trusses,
          are largely ornamental in character. They
          serve to round off what would otherwise be
          an angular outline, but do not support any of
          the weight of the structure.
          Above the lower platform two four-corner
          piers incline toward each other at a
          sharper angle. The iron columns are lighter
          and the spaces in the system of bracing are
          larger. High above the first platform, nearly
          400 feet from the ground, a second series of
          horizontal trusses binds the four piers to
          gether and forms the basis for a second land
          ing. These two platforms are glorious places
          St. Peter's,
          433 ft. Rouen
          Cathedral,
          470 ft.
          Statue of Wash- Column
          Liberty, ington Vendome,
          301 ft. Monument, 148 ft.
          500 ft.
          from which to view the city of Paris. They
          are so large that even very timid persons
          standing on them will lose all fear. The
          lower one is nearly half an acre in extent
          while the upper one is about one-third that
          size. From the platform a view of the coun
          try for forty miles around may be obtained.
          Above the second platform the four corner
          piers gradually approach each other and at
          length unite in one pier, at the top of which,
          nearty a fifth of a mile from the ground,
          there is a covered observatory, and above
          this rises a slender mast. Doubtless many
          thousand people will see Paris and ever so many
          square miles of surrounding country from the
          observatory during the summer. They will
          not have to walk up, for a gigantic elevator
          runs up through one of the piers to the very
          top. This elevator is of peculiar construction,
          for the carriage or truck, travels upward on
          a spiral track, while the car itself rises
          vertically, or rather as nearly vertically as
          the angle of the pier will allow.
          While the Eiffel tower was a stupendous
          conception, and will stand as completed
          the marvel of modern engineering, no new
          principles are involved in its construction.
          In fact, to an engineer, the most wonderful
          thing about the tower is its simplicity. The
          way for the Eiffel tower, both in conception
          and execution, was paved, after a fashion,
          by the work on the Garobit viaduct and the
          Taraes bridge, both of which were built by
          Eiffel. In fact, the construction of bridges
          and viaducts, without the use of scaffolding or
          false work, by making the several parts
          balance themselves as the work progresses,
          owes much to this French engineer.
          Gustavo Eiffel is a master of construction.
          It is said of him that he combines within
          himself the practical knowledge of the Eng
          lish engineer, the audacity of the American
          and the science and theories of the French
          man. He was born at Dijon, France, in 1S32,
          and was educated at the Central School of
          Sciences and Arts. He it was who first made
          practical use of compressed ah in cassions in
          the building of bridge foundations, in the
          erection of the great bridge at Bordeaux.
          TOP OF THE TOWER.
          M. Eiffel has been a busy man, indeed, these
          many years, but he found time, when the
          statue of Liberty Enlightening the World was
          to be set up in New ork Harbor, to design
          the skeleton framework which support the
          gigantic figure and at the same time firmly
          holds it to the granite pier on which it stands.
          A glance at the illustration will show to
          what extent the Eiffel tower overshadows all
          the famous tall structures of the world. In
          comparison with its 984 feet Cheops is dwarfed
          at 40. The Washington Monument is little
          less than 500 feet high, and the point of .he
          flame of Liberty's torch in New- York Harbor
          rises barely 300 feet in the air.
          The fees for ascending the Eiffel tower are
          five francs (1) to the cop, three francs
          (sixty cents) to the second platform an 1 two
          francs (forty cents) t. the first. The three
          platforms will hold 10,900 people.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87060190/1889-05-07/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+Paris+France+French+Expo+Exhibition+Worlds+Fair</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85033162/1900-05-18/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Paris+Exposition</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85032018/1894-01-31/ed-1/?sp=15&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+Paris+France+French+Worlds+Fair+1900+Exhibition</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83040198/1899-02-03/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+France+French+Paris+Exhibition+Worlds+Fair+Ladder+Clouds</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>A LADDER FROM THE CLOUDS
          Bach Will Be the Appearance of the
          Eiffel Tower of Parts When
          Painted.
          The Eiffel tower, say the gentlemen
          of esthetic temperament, must go.
          The Eiffel tower, say the gentlemen
          who know the law, must stay for some
          years yet. The Eiffel tower, say the
          esthetes. Is ugly, discouraging to the
          eye and an all-round nightmare. "Scaf
          fold I cries the carper. "Down with it
          It has no place in esthetic Paris,"
          "Impossible! objects the law. "When
          the company took a lease of it they
          got it for a term of 20 years.. You
          can't break the lease, and the time is
          nowhere up.
          "But, urges the esthete, "look at
          the shape, look at the size, look at the
          color! Is not the whole thing hideous"?
          If we can't destroy it we can at least
          improve it and lessen the offense to
          our senses."
          And so the Eiffel tower is going to be
          metamorphosed. It has. been in color
          a reddish brown, and it is the color to
          which the gentlemen with the fine ideas
          have long objected. They have called
          the tower a shameless creation and re
          peatedly ridiculed the commonplace
          tone of hue. And now they have pre
          v ailed, and the lower is going to be a
          thing of beauty, so far as that goes.
          Silver white is the color agreed upon,
          and it is urged that when the army of
          workmen have finished their painting
          the huge structure will look really not
          so bad after all. Ilalf a hundred men
          will be employed on the building, work
          ing hard every day for two months.
          And 50,000 kilogrammes of paint will
          be used up before the Eiffel tower has
          finally lost its brickdust coat and finds
          itself arrayed in the poetic covering
          which the esthetes have advised. Two
          coats of paint will be applied and the
          brushes will be busy.
          It has been objected that the tbwer
          has always had the appearance or hav
          ing been cast up in inartistic form by
          a careless earth. The tower has seemed
          to rise awkwardly from the ground,
          the critical have said. Why not give
          it such an arrangement as would sug
          gest the idea of dropping from the
          clouds? That would be a pleasing fan
          cy, and if the huge tower were lighted
          at regular intervals it would present a
          picture as of a brilliant creature of the
          clouds, and all the world would be lost
          in admiration. These plans were sug
          gested when the exposition of 1900 were
          tinder discussion, and they have been
          adopted. A ladder from the clouds.
          That was tbe idea. 'And with that the
          esthetic taste, was forced to be sat
          isfied.
          The Eiffel tower has long been the
          universal bed lamp of Paris. The great
          candle in the top would be sadly miss-d,
          even by those who have fought agair.t
          the continuance of the structure. That
          ever-swaying lantern is one of the won
          ders of the French capital. Y. Her
          aid.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1900-05-20/ed-1/?sp=43&amp;q=Feet+Tower+Eiffel+Paris+France+French+Worlds+Fair+Exhibition</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1903-10-25/ed-1/?sp=24&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+Doomed+Rocks+Wind+Paris+France+French+Gustav</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THE Eiffel Tower must come down.
          The authorities of Paris have so decreed.
          This iron spire, the tallest structure in the
          world, and the engineering feat of the last cen
          tury, \.i regarded as a dangerous plaything.
          When a high wind blows from the south the great
          ribbed structure trembles like a frightened horse.
          But let a stiff breeze come bowling down from the
          north and the tower vibrates until the china rattles in
          the cafes, and to those in the observatory at the apex the
          sensation is that of a ship fossed by heavy seas.
          The fact that the tower is more'sensitive to a wind
          from the north than from the south is regarded as proof
          of the structural weakness, and from this springs the
          theory of danger of collapse.
          It is almost twenty years since Gustav Eiffel began
          the work of building his sky-scraper. The mark of com
          pletion was set for 1889, Exposition year, and on March 31
          of that year the tower was thrown open to the public. It
          wa« the leading attraction of the big show, and it has
          not since ceased to attract attention and coin.
          The cost of building the structure was more than
          $1,000,000. Of that amount the French government appro
          priated $29L',000. Eiffel supplied the remainder, trusting
          for his reimbursement to the receipts from admission fees
          and other sources.
          In this he was not uisappolnted, as the profits of the
          first year were almost sufficient to make him whole.
          The lease held by Eiffel will expire in next March, and
          then, if the present plans of the city fathers are realized,
          the work of razing the unique structure will be started.
          The plan is to sell the tower to the highest bidder, the
          purchaser to be given a certain time in which to remove
          what Paris regards as almost a public menace.
          Except as a curio and an Investment for its builder,
          the tower has been somewhat of a failure.
          Much was expected in the scientific world from the
          metaphorical observatory, with its physical and biological
          laboratories, all 954 feet above ground. But little has
          come of this, the enterprise having taken on a rather
          commercial aspect.
          The Eiffel Tower will ever be considered a colossa*
          feat of engineering.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1907-03-10/ed-1/?sp=47&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+Gustav+Paris+France+French+Republic</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>GIGANTIC war wareye wareye
          eye that th a twill twillsweep will willsweep
          sweep the whole of ofFrance ofPranceher
          France Pranceher her fron frontiers fro1Zjers
          tiers jers her chains clzaillsof clzaillsoffortresses of offortresses
          fortresses and her herseaboard herscaboardsllch
          seaboard scaboardsllch such Is Isto isto
          to be the I further furthermission furthermisJion
          mission of Ithc the fa famous famOlls
          mOlls Eiffel Tower Toweri Towerof
          i of Paris ParisThis Par J JThis
          This struct strllcillrc strllcillrcere lire
          4 e ere r e c t c d a as s the thechief thechief
          chief curiosity of ofthe ofthe
          the Paris Exposi Exposition E 4posi 4position
          tion has outlived outlivedits
          its 11 usefulness in other respects and has hasbeen hasbeen
          been made the central point of the great greatwireless greatwireless
          wireless signal system of the French army armyand armyand
          and navy
          From the top of the tower which is
          984 feet from the ground roll1td officials of the thearmy thearmy
          army may direct military operations op ratio1Zs in any anyLift allYLftt
          Lift up your eyes and behold them that come from fromthe tromthe
          the NorthJer aclll 0 0URLNG 0D
          FlUNG the army manoeuvres last fall fallthe fallthe
          D the various corps were directed from fromthe fromthe
          the now station Later fleet movements movementsin mO mcnts mcntsin
          in the Englislrchannel El lis1 chRnnel and the Mediter Mediterranean M diter diterranean
          ranean wore ordered ord 6dwithout without a hitch in the samo samoway sarnotvaJr
          way wayQuite Quite lecently the scope scoP of communication communicationfirm
          comunicatio1f
          firm f m the tower towmlms has been Cxf rlendc1 ended so that no nOtY nOtYmessages v
          vmessages
          messages are exchanged e changed with London and Ber Berlin Berlin
          lin on the one onG side and with Tunis and Algiers Algierson Algierionthe
          on onthe the African coast on the other otherTte otherThe
          The work of equipping it for signal pur purposes purposes
          poses is now going on and it is expected to in inEtal instal
          Etal there the most complete coml lete system s stem of wire wireless wireleastelcir8P1ly
          less leastelcir8P1ly tdegrapny in the thewodd thewoddne world worldThe
          The French Frenchare are pleased with the idea of 1C 1Cbining re retaining
          taining the architectural curiosity curiosi ty and their theirjeamty tbcirFanity
          jeamty is tickled hy the plan to make it the theriost theost
          riost ost wonderful war eye on the globe globeIndeed glober
          r Indeed the enthusiastic people pcoJ le confidently confidentlysrpect confidentlyb
          b srpect ect in a short time tim to see 5e airships arriving arrivingt
          1t t and nd departing from this great steel stom stomfcn stomin
          fcn airship airshipstntion station nearly 1000 feet above earth earthBuilt earth1nt
          Built 1nt by the th famous engineer Gustavo Eif Eifr Eifrrr
          r
          rrr I
          part of ortlze the Republic and even for consider considerable cOlZsijerable
          able distances ovei tle tile frontier in adjolnlng adjolnlngcountries adj illi1lg
          illi1lgcOlilltries
          countries Its naval fleets In the thelYledi thelYledierrmzetlll Medi Mediterranean
          terranean errmzetlll the Bay Ba of Biscay the English EnglishChannel EllglishClza1l1zel
          Channel the North Sea or the Baltic B ltic will willbe willbc
          be In constant touch with the directing directingauthorities directilZgauthorities
          authorities In Paris ParisShould ParisShould
          Should France and England become becomeallies becolleallies
          allies in some future conflict direct com communication commtl1licat
          mtl1licat munication on with London can be maintained maintainedfrom mailltailledfrom
          from the Eiffel Tower Southward from fromit
          it waves of warning anJtSfypmmand Jm1lZmzd will willfloat j
          float into d Algeria 19cria and Tunis From this rc rcmarkable rcmarkable
          markable tower may issue orders that wilt wiltchange willdt willdtczange
          change the 7i of Europe v vfel
          czange map ap i iI iI iIel I I
          fel the tower was completed in March 1889 lSS9jn lSS9jntime in intime
          time to tOSCITe serve as 13 one of the notable features featur 5J of ofthe oftlte
          the exposition of that year ear It was the loading loadingattraction leallingattraction
          attraction of that big show and has never neversince neversinceceased since sinceceased
          ceased to draw visitors and coin coinIt coinIt
          It cost considerably over 1000000 to build buildtho buildtho
          tho tower for which 7000 tons of metal were wereused wereused
          used Of the cost 292000 was voted by tha thagovernment thlgovernmont
          government while the engineer supplied the therest thereat
          rest The profits for 1SS9 alone nearly paid nid tha thacost thacost
          cost
          Some idea of its height height984 984 fcot feotway niay be begained begained
          gained from a comparison with other structures structuresof
          of the world Tho Washington Monument at atWashington atVashington
          Washington D C is 555 feet tall the broad broadbrimmed broadbrimmed
          brimmed hat of William Penn on Philadel Philadelphias Philadelphias
          phias City Hall is 547 feet above the pave pavement pavement
          ment the dome of St Peters in Rome rises risesto risesto
          to only 448 feet while the great pyramid of ofCheops ofCheops
          Cheops is but 486 feet high highFrom highFrom
          From the top of the Eiffel Tower on onjlclear onjlclearday tclear tclearday
          day one can see about eightyfive mUei At Atnight Atni
          night ni ht a searchlight from this eminence stabs the thesurrounding thesurrounding
          surrounding darkness darknessAt darknessAt
          At its base this wonderful tower covers coversnearly coversnnarb
          nearly twc and a half acres of ground Its
          mt tmTf iY Wf Wflower
          lower section consists of four builtup iron col columns c ll llumns
          umns each of which consists of four smaller smallercolumns smaUercolumns
          columns resting on masonry piers piersSpringing piersSpringin
          Springing gracefully upward tho th four fourmain IOlrmain
          main columns curve toward each other until
          020 feet above the surface they join in si single singlecolumij singlecolum
          columij colum Above this the long needle of the thetower thetocr
          tower rises rie 3G4 feet higher higherAt1 higherAtlS0
          At1 AtlS0 ISO feet at 3SO feet and again a ain at 006 006feet 908feet
          feet there are platforms which are reached by byelevators byelevators
          elevators as well as by b stairs stairsFrom stairsFrom
          From the t e highest highcstplatform platform a winding stair stairway stairway
          way climbs to the very pinnacle of the struc structure strueture
          ture but this part has never been open to the thepublic theBublic
          public publicWhen
          When qen these different platforms are can canverted CQ CQverted
          verted in into tn airship stations the French will in indeed indeed
          deed possess pOSdc a novelty of which they may b bproud bproud
          proud proudThey They are daring enough to attempt almost almostanything am06tanything
          anything A few f w years ago a o the government set settled setiled
          tled in a startling way a l difference di er cc of opinion opinionbetween opihionbetwecn
          between the Minister 321rinB ri e and the Naval NavalBoard ava avaBoard
          Board of Construction ConstructionL r rL
          L Pelletan the Minister llin st r thou thought ht nioctera niocterabattleships m d m
          mhattleships
          battleships were being made in too complicated complicatedand QIIiplroatedand
          and delicate a fashion Tho Th maze of electrical electricalw3res eloctricaliCs
          w3res iCs and other machinery upon which the theWorking theWorking
          Working of the turrets depended would be put putoujof putitof
          oujof commission he argued by the impact of ofa ofllcvy
          a heavy shell shelll hcll hcllrt
          l Et is impossible to build a floating fortress fortresslike ortress ortresslike
          like a watch he declared declaredWell declaredrell
          Well rell retorted the other tuthoritio tuthoritiothere authoritiCNthoro
          there is a way to settle the matter if you will willorder willorder
          order a tost wo shall see who is right rightSo rj bt1 bt1So
          So to the theainazem611t amazement of Franco FraDCcrof of the theworld thewqrl
          world wqrl 1 in fact fftcttno the now no battleship Suffrea prlda prldaof pri priof
          of the thenll navy was ordered out for the test to b bfired bired
          fired upon pon by b a istr ship shipJust shipJust
          Just outside tho picturesque pictur que harbor of ofBrest ffBrest
          Brest she sl1 was anchored her decks dC ks cleared for foraction forAction
          action To T a within a few hundred yards of her hersteamed her5teamcd
          steamed the big battleship Massena which let letgo Jetgo
          go full ard fair at the other ther with one of her hertwelveinch berIreinch
          twelveinch Ireinch ggins gginsThe 5 5Tliegrodt
          The Tliegrodt great shell struck the Suffrens turret turretSQuaToly turrets
          SQuaToly s r 1y 1ebou cabouruled andburst 1I1d J ur5t into frafm frIrie frIrieA at8 at8A
          A jlarg nr o olaqk 1a splotch ajepaared on the e tacteirr tacteirrthajr J i
          thajr thntW ras allfttio damage dan aCrea1parant aCrea1parantWffiativ apparent
          apparentAV5if
          AV5if Wffiativ veT r damago dam i6fwi was llbno done to the U1 Di6chtt miklr miklr5sm t
          tQft
          5sm of Qft the e turrets turretswaS wasVncver imer maderiiubiic m d ltpbHc buir buirtw h e
          tw two ahoep sh p tliqt 1 tl1adbce had been 1lmpnsoneLin imprisoned iii the tur turicts
          turicb
          icts were weri not injured injuredSo injurodSo
          So when wl ID the Fronch Fr ch complete the equips equipsmcnt equip7DIDt
          mcnt of tha Eiffel Ei el Tower Tw as tho thceyeUd eye and braiui braiuitflfiieir brai 1 1i
          tflfiieir i 1 military lit operations oP 1ati DS thby ili Y win donktiiijifc do doiT
          iT df
          t i
          f W
          I
          c III I Ihave
          hare some startling innorMon to present presentUpon preltcntUPOlll
          Upon UPOlll a peace footing tile French ariayc arIlIYQlt arIlIYQlts n nsists
          sists s 8tti of about 550000 men the total war warstrength W2irstr
          str strength th of the nation is figurjwl figul l at oraettliiK oraettliiKover
          over over 4600000 4600000Wpre 4600 000 000Tere
          Wpre Tere the annies an ie cf France Franceo o inTMie in ier iermany er ermaiiy
          many England 1 11lalld or Italy they coUld be diraifced diraifcedby dire W Wby
          by the Eiffel Tower station far infc in those t coun countries e UIl UIltriesto
          tries triesto to the centals of England E Jnd ntd Geratmnv Geratmnvdid GerJBatydid
          did they succeed iu getting getti that fan fanBat farBut
          Bat if the main duty were defense of the therepublics therepublics
          republics home territory the wireless wirel s aerrice aerricewould 5er 5erwouJd
          would probably pro ftbJ be even better as more or less lesspermanent JesgpermaJKnt
          permanent stations could be erected V 10D iig the tbeline theJi
          line Ji e of frontier fr tDtier fortifications from which to tocommunicate toOOIDJDuuicate
          communicate with Eiffel EiffelWhen Ei eL eLmen
          When men the new frontier line was drawn d awn by byGermany oyGerman
          Germany German after the war of 1S70 it was so ar arranged arranged
          ranged that all the strongest positions should shouldmi ouJd ouJdthe
          mi the German side of the line France Franceof Fraooc1sof
          of defense stands stan s back from the theraiflaer te tetier
          tier igt t Verdun Toul Belfort and Bipan Bipancon san sanCOlt
          con conThe The defenses d fenses of Paris are fifty fiftymilsiay fiftymilsiayfrom milo
          xjiray xjirayfrom
          from the ci city extending around it in a ciioli C r of offortifications ofortjiicaticl
          fortifications 8 so that an invading army the theGermane tbcGermaD6
          Germane for or example examp1eeven even after overcoaajng overcoaajngthe
          the first rst line of defense defen e would have to break breakthrough b k kthrou
          through throu h this inner ring ringFor riD riDFor
          For that reason there will never be indjfcr indjfcrsiege a r rof
          siege of Paris in the same sam sense as the t o last l5tShoud iiSL iiSLShould
          Should an enemy get past the fiftymile chain if ifforts ff ffforts
          forts there would be no other obstacle in m match matching tcIi tcIiupon
          ing upon the city citywar citylIerCp
          lIerCp then is the nccess 1 fora vj vjwar
          war eye at tlie capital overlooking overlookingill all the mili military mlhtary
          tary area within the frontiers frontiersThe j jThe
          The army corps at 2Taacy N ancy would undoubted undoubtedly
          ly 1 bear the irst 1 rst shock of a German advance advanceerery advaneftery
          erery turn of the tide of conflict must mustD Jta known knownat kDowrat
          at once to Paris so that the other corp6 corpS couid couidbe C uk ukbe
          be promptly moed like men on a chessboard chessboardIn
          In a similar way the fleets eets under unfI ihe tri tricotor tricolor
          color could he moved Frances great sav JfllVfl wouU W4uldcemented wouUbe
          be cemented ijtto ia a ntobilo and effectai effeeif a whale whaleShe
          She S e IMS in m1ictiveBerri active aerriee eQi7 557 figktiag ting sh s t of gfH aH
          aHktads</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1907-05-18/ed-1/?sp=26&amp;q=Dangerous+Painting+World+Eiffel+Tower+Paris+France+French+Republic+Gustav</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>I MOST DANGERO1 NEW COATS FOR The Trocadero m Seen Through the "Lege" of the Tower.
          Height of the Great Tower as Compared to Some of the World's Tallest Structures. Special
          Correspondence of The Star. PARIS, May A, 1907. A painter has Just fallen from the Eiffel
          Tower. Four more men must fall to make the awful average of the most dangerous painting
          Job in the world?repeated every six years only. They are repainting the Eiffel Tower, and
          all Paris is concerned about the color, on which depends whether the gigantic mass of iron
          shall be the eyesore or the glory of the capital. Its first shade was "dead leaf," In
          1889. When the sun lit it up to hazy golden with an unreal effect of Jeweler's fragility,
          even the artists who now corse it admitted that the Eiffel Tower had its nobility. In
          1896, after immense discussion, they repainted It orange, magnetic currents even more than
          light and weather having turned it to a dingy chocolate, heavy and obtrusive. In strong
          sun the orange showed gleaming copper or red gold. Oscar Wilde declared It magnificent.
          Puvis de Chavannes threatened to blow It up with dynamite. From this period dated the bad
          name the tower acquired as a colossal piece of engineering vulgarity, usurping the
          artistic note of Paris. Then, for the exposition, they painted it "sun color." In bright
          lights the tower became a thing of glory once again. "All Depends Upon the Faint." "All
          depends upon the paint!" declares the city's architect, Bouyard, "a fact which shows the
          utter inartistic character of the Titan 1^3 intruder. The pyramids ol Egypt were
          originally cased with gleaming marble; but its present lack does not detract from the
          artistic appropriateness of the pyramids to their situation!" The tower gleamed sun color
          seven years agoi But the atmospheric electricity received every hour since then by such an
          unprecedented mass of iron reaching into the air so high is Incalculable. Conducting tubes
          a foot and a half in diameter lead it down the four niles to flftv feet be low the
          water-bearing stratum; but the effect on the paint la there for every one to see. It does
          not crack the paint off. The paint simply disappears, leaving the ugly chocolate, the
          dingy brown of the oxidising iron. It Is the tower's way of "calling for new victims.
          Fifty painters, working continuously together, take three months to do a ingle coat Few
          tourists realise- the immense proportions of the tower, but Parisian!, by experience, show
          you a peculiar phenomenon of Its deceptive symmetry. They take you In a cab close to the
          tower. It looks heavy and chunky. It seems sinking into the earth from lU weight. Half a
          mile distant from that oab the tower grows higher and slenderer. It seems to lift Itself
          from the earth, like a person rising from his knees. "Why, It's bigger than before!" you
          say. At a mil* distant-It seems quite as near. The river boats ttmt flit beside It now
          look tiny. The buildings round about are growing small. But the tower grows! Then at two
          miles? from the heights above Passy?It appears A 4kin? A# litfhtnMa hl alAn^nrAf Efc
          IIIIUB Vi u fc?v? gutiUVBWi ?and more open In Its lacework than when you gaped at its foot
          almost disappointed! In a country town thirty miles from Paris I have sat at night and
          watched Its leaxchltsht! Some Comparisons. Tou think Niagara Falls are high? They are 105
          feet, and St. Paul's Cathedral, Lon- 1 don. is 404 feet. Niagara Falls could de scend from
          below St. Paul's dome. Now place St. Paul's beside the Eiffel tower. It reaches only to
          the second platform of the tower?the real beginning of its slender shaftl Place the Eiffel
          tower beside the greatest buildings of the world. The great pyramid does not reach to Its
          Intermediate platform. Neither does the spire of the Cologne 1 Cathedral. Only one 'set of
          buildings, nevertheless, are higher than the Cologne Cathedral Bplre. They are the
          sky-scrapers of American dtles, the tallest actually existing being, say, 6S6 feet high.
          It would not reach to the tower's intermediate platform, either. The loftiest masonry
          construction In the world is to be the Singer building extension, at the corner of Liberty
          street and Broadway, New Torlc. Beating any other J i American sky-scraper by 57 feet, it
          will i stick 612 feet into the air. And yet even j It will not reach to the Eiffel tower's
          inter- i mediate platform 1 You can easily detect this intermediate i platform half way up
          the slender shaft of 3 the Eiffel tower. In the nearer photographs j It shows for what it
          is?a mere platform for styftlng passengers from one set of ele- t vators to another, built
          In the center of the 1 the time you git left. This yere man. Bob Hampton, Is my prisoner,
          an' I'll take him to Cheyenne. If I have ter brain every tough t in Glencaid to do It.
          Thet's me, gents." 1 "Oh, come oft; you can't run your notions j igin the whole blame
          moral sentiment of c this camp." c "Moral sentiment! I'm backln' up the t aw, not moral
          sentiment, ye cross-eyed c jeer-slinger, an' if ye try edgin' up ther l mother stfep I'll
          plug you with this '45.' c There was a minute or hesitancy while i iie men below
          conferred, the marshal f ooking contemptuously down upon them, c lis revolver gleaming
          ominously in the v lght. Evidently the group hated to go back without the prisoner. j "Oh,
          come on. Buck, show a little hoss i
          fense." the leader sang out " We've got c
          very feller in camp along with us, an' 1
          :here ain't no show fer the two o' ye to t
          lold out against that sort of an outfit." 8
          Mason smiled and patted the barrel of hia
          -olt-
          " Oh. go to biases! wnen i want any aa- t
          rice, Jimmie, I'U send fer ye."
          Some one flred, the ball. digging up the f
          10ft earth at the marshal' s feet, and fling-
          ng it in a blinding cloud into Hampton's f
          yes. Mason' s answer was a sudden fusi-
          ade. which sent the crowd flying helter- 8
          skelter into the underbrush. One among
          hem staggered and half fell, yet succeeded
          Wmcelf nnt nf slffht V
          "Great Scott, If I don't believe I winged
          Fanjes!" the shooter remarked cheerfully,
          -eaching back Into his pocket for more f
          cartridges. "Maybe them boys will be a
          )lt more keerful If they once onderstand v
          hey're up agin the real thing. Well, per-
          laps I better skin down, fer I reckon It's
          table ter be rifles next" t
          It was rifles next, and the "wincing" of
          US PAINTING JOE
          EIFFEL TOWER C
          A Comparison of the Relative Heigl
          Build
          The Great Pyramid. 480 ft. Wanhington Monument,
          ftt. Paul'*, 404 ft. Blackpool Tower, 516 ft.
          Monument, 202 ft. Nelaon
          shaft and not extending to Its exterior.
          In photographs of the tower at a greater
          distance It appears more clearly?almost
          like a story. And it is 647 feet from the
          ground.
          High Above the Ground.
          The third platform?which looks like the
          brim of a hat at the top?is 911 feet from
          the ground. Niagara, with a suspension
          bridge 100 feet high over it, could easily
          fall between it and the intermediate platform?above
          the top of the Singer extension;
          while the true top of the tower is still
          74 feet higher!
          VIotroxA Poll- 0
          a tu^ui u. i- ano nuuiu uavc niuic uiatt o Ui" j
          flcient room, In fact, to fall between any of
          the sections of the Eiffel' tower. Even the
          squat-looking first platform. Immediately
          above the four legs, is 191 feet high.
          The ground space inclosed/ by those four
          legs exceeds two acres ana a half. Few
          Parisians, even, realize that it has broad
          and spacious stairways to the very top.
          They can accommodate 2,000 persons per
          hour to the second platform; and so on, In
          proportion. This is without oountlng the
          elevators. With the stairways, they can
          take 3,200 persons per hour to the first
          platform, and so on lh proportion.
          The restaurants, theater and beer hall of
          4.VI. A i. .1.44. Ml 1 1* ?A
          luio iii01 pittuvi m win uuiu i,wv peruuuv til
          one time: its four exterior galleries will
          oontaln 4.000 persons; its Interior terraces
          and galleries (It has really two stories) will
          give accommodation to 400 more.
          The second platform can hold 3,000 persons.
          The intermediate platform and the
          summit hold 1,000 more. Add 8,200 persons
          mounting and descending the stairways
          and elevators, and the total "saturation"
          of the tower becomes 13,200. peoplemore
          than the population of a good-sised
          little city!
          The painting of the tower Is gigantic
          Job by reason of its peculiarly open structure.
          The vast edifice weighs actually
          under 8,000 tons. This Is by reason of its
          perfect mechanical form?lace work in iron.
          Its total surface being, however, enormously
          greater than its mere exterior surface.
          over thirty tons of liquid paint are
          required to give it a single coat!
          Fifty painters, working continuously together.
          take three months to do a single
          coat. In 1889 three only fell; the tower had
          already had its eighteen victims during the
          construction, and every one went carefully
          by habit; they had acquired a collective Instinct
          of the danger of it.
          Cost Sevan Lives.
          In the repainting of 1896 seven painters
          fell. They were but few of them the men
          of 1889. They had no Eiffel tower experience,
          but they had all the French artisan's
          flaring, born of trade vanity and fear to
          seem afraid. When, after Ave men had
          been killed, the direction would have protected
          them with life-saving belts and rigting,
          they rebelled to a man! As a remit.
          two others fell before the job was
          finished.
          In 1900 the direction called for painters
          who had worked upon the tower In 1896.
          They responded In a mass?and asked exorbitant
          wages! When, however. It was
          finally got Into their heads that the selec
          tlon was being made, not tor their skiii as
          painters or their personal good looks, but
          is an act of pure humanity, they went to
          work at the old advance of 80 per cent
          ibove the union scale?on condition of not
          being required to disgrace themselves with
          lifesaving rigging!
          Such Is the French building artisan?malon,
          line roofer, carpenter, painter?pigeaded
          set, unchanging and vain beyond
          Big Jim, however it may have Inspired
          autlon, also developed fresh animosity in
          he hearts of his followers, and brought
          orth evidences of discipline in their ap?
          I _u.ii l
          roacn. peering ai-russ wie mimeiiug
          lump pile, the besieged were able to perceive
          the dark figures cautiously advancing
          hrough the protecting brush; they spread
          tut widely until their two flanks were close
          n against the wall of rock, and then the
          leadly rifles began to spit spitefully, the
          alls casting up the soft dirt in clouds or
          lattening against the stones. The two men
          Touched lower, hugging their pile of slag,
          inable to perceive even a stray assailant
          irlthin range of their ready revolvers,
          lampton remained cool, alert, and motion
          ess, striving in vain 10 discover some means
          if escape, but the little marshal kept grlmy
          cheerful, creeping constantly from point
          o point in the endeavor to get a return
          hot at his tormentors.
          "This whole blame cotintry Is full of disharged
          sojers," he growled, "an' they know
          heir biz all right. I reckon them fellers is
          iretty sure t6 git one ot us yit anyhow,
          hey've got us cooped. Say, Bob, thet lad
          rawllng yonder ought to be in reach, an'
          t's our bounden duty not to let the boys
          It too gay."
          Hampton tried the shot suggested, eJevat
          ig considerable to overcome distance. There
          pas a yell, and a swift skurrylng backward
          rhlch caused Mason to laugh, although
          leither knew whether this result arose from
          right or wound.
          'Bilged ter teach 'em manners onct In a
          phlle, or they'll Imbibe a fool notion they
          ;ln come right 'long up yere without no in ite.
          'Tala't fer long, nohow, 'less all
          hem guys are ijuts."
          Hampton turned nis head and looked so
          I
          t IN THE WORLD I'
          j
          OST MANY LIVES
          i i
          i ;i II
          II
          t.,-v Ik I
          its of Some of the World'i Highests
          Ings.
          55S ft. Singer building, 812 ft.
          Cologne Cathedral. 515 ft. Eiffel Tower. 686 ft.
          Monument, 175 ft. Cleopatra's Needle, 09 ft.
          words with an honorable collective trad*4
          vanity!
          The reault was five men killed In 1900.
          Now, last Friday, there fell the first victim
          of the series of 1007, though the actual
          painting has not yet begun. He was a kind
          of foreman, climbing about, looking over
          the upper, more dangerous points. He fell
          from a point a trifle below the third plat
          form, struck twice going down, deflecting
          his fall slightly; yet his body sank almost
          five feet into the earth of a flower bed* r
          beside the southeast pile. When the Jallylike
          mass was taken out of the hole It had
          made, It was seen that the lower end of hla
          right leg tibia, or shin bone, had been
          forced through the sole of his foot!
          Yet he was a man of tower experienc?kr
          having worked on the painting jobs of
          1895 and 1900. Two-thirds of the men now
          gathering and making their platforms
          ready at the foot of the monument hvq
          had the same experience.
          "Glad to B? Back."
          "I'm glad to b? back on the quiet steady
          six months job?two coats this iime!" said
          one of them. "It Is charming up thsre. The
          sensation Is fascinating, I assure you. I
          was never so happy as during those three
          months of 1900. One Is alone In the delicious
          Dure Rip. The hlllA ImmanBltv la oil
          around. One hears no sounds. All la
          peace!"
          "Yea, but good-bye to Saturday evenings!"
          laughed another. "Good-bye to Sunday
          diversion! Got to keep our stomachs
          In first-class condition. When the digestion
          is 'off,' the eye is not keen and the nerve*
          are shaky. I would not go up If I felt the
          slightest 'pain in the hair!'
          "Yes, we've got to measure the wine we
          put In our water," was the general agre*
          ment. Half the men who fell In 1900, they
          remember, did so from foolhardiness just
          aiter lunch hour, when Dutch courage,
          born of the French artisan's Invariable red.
          wine, led them to Incautious doings.
          "And*the othersT" I asked.
          A grizzled old fellow In a long whit*
          smock shrugged his shoulder and crooked
          his neck non-commlttally.
          "The smell of paint for some," he said.
          "And the high winds that blew around the
          tvn?s. ai 1110 iuu it us ncariy tuwayb plowlng
          terrifically. That big spire shaft swayf
          two yards. To some It gives a sickening
          feeling when It sways most. Visitors don^
          feel It?they are walking about the platforms?and
          two yards, even, Is little In proportion
          to that height, but when you sit
          there on your little scaffold, painting a few
          hundred of the 2,600,000 rivets, there will
          come a sudden 'goneness'?then look out
          my children, shut your eyes ana pull your*
          selves together!"
          "I fear only storms!" said a young painted
          of thirty. "I remember well the storm of
          1000 when two of the copalns went down,
          down?Dleu! I see them! The storm cam*
          uu uitujK ttiiu angry, ureal arups sirucK our
          faces, blinding our eyes. Lightning flashes
          played all around us. We could smell th?
          electricity! It made us nervous. The thunder
          was something awful. The tower wu
          struck again and agp.in!" "And
          you painters?" I asked.
          "We Just held on where we were."
          He stopped awkwardly. It la unlucky to
          talk such things. The talk "threw a cold,"
          as the Trench say. The young painter
          "gave himself countenance by getting
          busy with a rigging. The .oid grizzled one
          spoke up to cheer them. Frenchmen being
          mercurial, responslvel
          "Va done, go to, my children. It Is a good
          Job, six months of sure work, quiet an)
          peaceful, with high pay and much consul*
          eration from the bosses, in the pure air up
          there, it will do us all good to our health-*
          quoi, like a summer In the mountains!"
          STERLING HEILIO.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020657/1923-12-29/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=who+built+eiffel+tower</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Engineer Who Built
          Eiffel Tower Is Dead
          PARIS, Dec. 29.—Alexander Gus
          tave Eiffel, engineer who built the
          Eiffel Tower, died yesterday at</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86091349/1921-08-12/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=who+built+eiffel+tower</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014519/1926-07-29/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=who+built+eiffel+tower</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Q- Who built the Eiffel Tower
          and why was it built, and when?
          A. It was constructed by the
          engineer Alexandre Eiffel as a fea
          ture of the Paris Exposition in 18S9.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1917-08-11/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=who+built+eiffel+tower</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Engineer Eiffel Says It Would
          Take, 3(1 Months nt l.raaf.
          PAIUS, Aug. 11. Alexandre Ous.
          tave Eiffel, tho engineer who built tho
          Eiffel Tower, commenting on John
          Qcnckcn's project to build a tunnel
          under tho English Channel, as ca
          bled from America, says thlrty-tlve
          months, not thlrty-flvo days, would
          be needed. Eiffel adds:
          "The preparatory work of such an
          undertaking would require a long
          time transporting and Installing ma
          chinery and curtaln.ng workmen.
          And how would wo got rid of the ma
          terial excavated fast enough, If the
          machine bores 100 feet an hour?"</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1924-04-26/ed-1/?sp=23&amp;q=who+built+eiffel+tower</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-hypnotism</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86064205/1887-06-29/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=hypnosis+HYPNOTIC+hypnotic+hypnotism+hypnotized</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>EYPNOTIC PHENOMENA
          Marrelous Demonstrations bj Eminont
          French Scientists Peisons and
          Objects Made Invisible at Will
          sterlonsEffects
          o
          Effects Produced l y the Use
          Magnets Wise Men
          Mystified
          Boston Herald
          One of the most notable features of the
          scientific tendencies of the present day is
          the extraordinary interest taken in the in
          vestigation ofthosejeculiar physical and
          psychical conditions now known collec
          tively under the name of hypnotism
          varying from lethargy catalepsy etc to
          somnambulism Until quite recently
          these investigations have been frowned
          upon and taboed in scientific circles and
          the fact that any man of scientific inclina
          tions was known to feel an interest in
          matters associated with mesmerism or
          animal magnetism was sullicient to
          make him an object of suspicion and in
          jure his good standing among his fellow
          scientists The result of these socalled
          investigations instituted by the French
          academy pronouncing in effect the whole
          subject a humbug and delusion has lain
          like an interdict upon further re
          searches and the whole matter was left
          over for the most parr to charlatans or
          to persons hardly capable of forming
          sound judgment or proceeding according
          to the accurate methods demanded by
          modern science Science however in
          the remarkable progress made of late
          23 advanced so far upon certain lines
          vt It has been hardly possible to pro
          od further in those directions without
          leering upon the forbidden fied There
          re the old signboards against trespass
          is have bten taken down For
          mesmerism that verbal scarecrow has
          been substituted hypnotism which
          word has had a wonderfully legitimizing
          effect while animal magnetism that
          once llouted idea has been proven to be
          sn existing fact by methods as accurate
          as those adopted by Faraday or
          Edison to verily their observations
          EFFORTS OK SCIENTISTS
          Many of the most eminent scientists of
          Europe are now devoting themselves
          assiduously to these researches Periodi
          cals making a specialty of the subject are
          now published in France Germany and
          England A catalogue of the recent
          literature of hypnotism and related phe
          nomena compiled by Max Dessoir was
          printed in the number of the German
          magazine called the Sphinx for February
          of this year and this catalogue occupied
          nine pages The list is limited to those
          words written on the lines laid under the
          methods of the modern school all books
          being excluded whose authors hold to
          mesmeric theories or who are even
          professional magnetizers The catalogue
          is therefore as strictly scientific as pos
          sible and being classified with German
          thoroughness under the different branches
          of the subject such as hysterohypnot
          ism suggestion fascination etc
          it will prove a valuable assistance to the
          udent
          In this country the interest of scient
          1s has not yet been aroused to an ex
          mt comparable to that of European in
          jstigators Old prejudices have not
          5tirely lost their potency One of the
          most eminent professors of s leading
          university is said to have been subjected
          to ridicule from his colleagues because of
          a marked interest shown in the subject
          and a Boston physician of high standing
          within a few months confided to the
          writer that he had made use of hypnotic
          methods with gratifying success in the
          case of a patient where ordinary reme
          dies hd proved unavailing but he did
          not venture to make the result public
          since his fellowdoctors might be inclined
          to condemn his action as irregular
          A work embracing the whole subject
          has lately appeared in Paris and as it is
          to form a volume of the valuable Inter
          national Scientific series published in
          English French German and Italian it
          can hardly fail to diffuse a correct popu
          lar understanding of the results thus far
          attained The book is called Le Mag
          netism Animal Animal Magnetism
          and its authors are Messrs Alfred Binet
          and Charles Fere of the medical staff of
          the Saltpetrier Hospital for Nervous Dis
          orders in Paris It gives a history of the
          patient researches conducted at that in
          stitution by the medical staff under the
          celebrated Professor Charcote during the
          past nine years These experiments have
          been prosecuted according to the most
          exact scientific methods and with the
          most extreme caution The endeavor
          has been to obtain first of all the
          most elementary psychic phenomenon
          and to test every step in the
          investigations by separate experiments
          specially devised to prove the good faith
          of the subject and the reality of his hal
          lucination to eliminate the possibility of
          unconscious suggestion to establish re
          lations with similar phenomena of disease
          or health in tne domain of physiology
          and to note the modifications which can
          be brought about by altering the condi
          tions of the experiments The authors
          possess the great scientific virtue of
          never dogmatizing In the entire book
          not a single law is laid down not a
          single hypothesis is advanced which is
          not reached by the most improved in
          ductive processes A great service of
          the book lies in its enunciation of new
          and trustworthy methods for studying
          the physiology of the brain in health and
          disease while It brings into the realm of
          physical experiment vexed questions ot
          psychology heretofore given over to met
          aphysical methods exclusively
          THE HYPNOTIC SLEEP
          is described as a different form of natu
          ral sleep and all the causes which bring
          on fatigue are capable of bringing on
          hypnotism on suitable subjects Two
          of the leading hypnotic states are lethar
          gy and catalepsy the former being anala
          gous to deep sleep and the latter to a
          light slumber In lethargy the respirato
          ry movements are slow and deep cat
          alepsy slight shallow very slow and
          separated by a long interval In lethargy
          the application of a magnet over the re
          gion of the stomach causes profound mod
          ifications in the breathing and circulation
          while there is eo such effect in catalepsy
          This shows the connection of hypnotism
          with magnetism and various other ex
          periments with magnets have produced
          some wonderful results Here it may be
          added that Dr Geesmam a Vienna
          scientist who has made a specialty of
          hypnotic 8titdies has Invented and suc
          cessfully applied an Instrument called a
          hypnoscope consisting of an arrangement
          of magnets for the purpose of ascertain
          ing whether any persons is a good hyp
          notic subject
          The experiments demonstrate that
          sensation In the hypnotic states varies
          Detween the two opposite poles of
          hypetcc3thesia and antesthesia in other
          words the senses may be extraordinarily
          excited as in somnambulism or as in
          lethargy they may be extinct except
          sometimes hearing In somnambulism
          the field of vision and acutebess of sight
          are about double hearing is made very
          acute and smell is so intensely develop
          ed that a subject can find by scent the
          fragments of a card previously given to
          him to feeJ and torn up and hidden The
          memory of somnambulism is similarly
          exalted When awakened the subject
          does not as a rule remember anything
          that occurred when he was entranced
          but when again hypnotized his memory
          includes all the facts of his sleep his life
          when awake and his former sleeps
          ltichet attests how somnambules recall
          with a luxury of detail scenes in which
          they have taken part and places they
          have visited long ago M one of
          his somiambules sings the air of the
          second act of the opera LAfricaine when
          she is asleep but cnnot remember a
          note of it when awake
          There is a theory that no experience
          wlmtever of a person is lost to the mem
          ory it is only the power to recall it that
          is defective The authors of this work say
          that while the exaltation of the memory
          during somnambulism does not give ab
          solute proof to the theory that nothing is
          lost it proves at any rate that the mem
          ory of preservation is much greater than
          is generally imagined in comparison with I tauce of
          ing recollection more
          or less vivid per
          sists for a lew seconds then becomes ef
          faced This forgetfulness is even more
          marked in the case of hypnosis On re
          turning to natural consciousness the sub
          ject cannot recompose o single one of the
          scenes in which he has played his part as
          a witness or actor The loss howeveri3
          not complete for often a word or two is
          sufficient to bring back a whole scene
          though this word or two coming from
          operator to subject partakes more or less
          of the nature ot a suzgestion
          SUGGESTION
          Suggestion by which is meant the
          production of thoughts and actions on the
          part of the subject through some indica
          tion or bint given by the operator is
          found to be analagous to dreaming Say
          the authors All suggestion consists
          essentially in acting on a person by an
          idea every effect suggested is the re
          sultant of a phenomenon of ideation but
          we must add that the idea is but an
          outward sign taken alone it is only in
          dicative of some physiological process
          which Is alone capable of producing a
          material effect Persons vary in their
          susceptibility to suggestion For sug
          gesiion to succeed the subject must have
          naturally fallen or been artifically
          thrown into the state of morbid re
          ceptivity but it is difficult to deter
          mine accurately the conditions of susges
          tionability However we may mention
          two The first is the mental inertia or
          the subject the consciousness
          is completely empty an idea is suggest
          ed and reigns supreme over the slumber
          ing consciousness The second
          is psychic hyperexcitability the cause of
          the aptitude for suggestion From the
          standpoint of psychology the explanation
          of the effects of suggestion is to be found
          in the association of ideas Suggestion
          in its positive aspect is nothing eise than
          the throwing Into action of a mental as
          sociation preexisting in the spirit
          of the hypnotic For example we
          say to a patient Look you have a
          bird in your apron and no sooner arc
          these simple words pronounced than she
          sees the bird feels it with herfingersand
          sometimes even hears it sing All these
          ideas are associated in the mind by habit
          and consequently they are called into
          action Again in place of speech we
          engage the attention of the patient and
          when her gaze has become settled and
          obediently follows all our movements we
          imitate with the hand the motion of an
          object which dies Soon the patient
          cries Oh what a pretty bird How
          has a simple gesture produced so singu
          lar an effect Again by the association
          of ideas But this case differs from the
          preceding in being only an association of
          resemblance
          It is admitted however that Ihe hy
          pothesis ol the association of ideas only
          partly covers the facts of suggestion even
          when stretched to include resemblances
          For instance When we charge the brain
          of an entranced patient with some strange
          idea such as On awakening you will
          rob Mr Soandso of his handkerchief
          and on awakening the patient accom
          plishes the thet commanded there is
          nothing more than an image associated
          with an act In point of fact the patient
          has appropriated and assimilated the idea
          of the experimenter She does not pas
          sively execute a strange order but the
          order has passed in her consciousness
          from passive to active We can go as
          far as to say that the patient has the will
          to steal This state is complex and ob
          scure hitherto no one has explained ifc
          If fgf1
          suggestions impelling tq
          tion offer enigma how much more djfsuc
          gestions that inhabit Thjf t ct8
          eSot
          gestion of a portrait on a white card
          which is then shuilisd up with a dozen
          cards all alike On awakening the sub
          ject is asked to run over the collection
          without being told the reason
          why it is wished When he comes
          to the card on which had been lo
          cated the imeginary portrait he at once
          perceives it One detail of these ex
          periments is very significant Supposing
          we show the imaginary portrait at a dis
          the memory of reproduction or recollec eyes the card
          changes may be made out of his sight but
          the image is invariably seen In accordance
          with the primitive conditions although
          absolutely no difference is detected by
          the normal vision between the two blank
          surfaces of the sheet
          One experiment brings out this fact
          clearly On a white sheet ol paper is
          placed a card equally white with a fine
          point but without touching the paper
          the contour of the card is followed while
          the idea of a line traced in blacfi is sug
          gested to the subject The subjectwhen
          awakened is asked to fold the paper ac
          cording to these imaginary line3 lie
          holds the paper at the distance at which
          it was a the moment of the suggestion
          and folds it in the form of a rectangle
          exactly superposable on the card
          A curious experiment in the same line
          has been often repeated by Professor
          Charcot The subject is given the sug
          wo yards from the subjects
          appears white whereas a
          tion It is evident they say that in I real photograph would appear gray It
          a great number of caseswhere we believe is gradually brought nearer the imagin
          the memory is completely blotted out ary portrait at last appears but it is
          it is
          nothing
          of the kind
          The trace is
          always there but what is lacking is the
          power to evoke it and it is highly prob
          able that if we were subjected to hyp
          notism or the action of suitable excitants
          memories to all appearances dead might
          be revived
          A comparison between the phenomena
          of awakeuing from natural and artificial
          sleep is instituted In the case of dream
          necessary for it to be much nearer than
          an ordinary photograph for the patient to
          recognze the subject By means of opera
          glasses we can make the patient recog
          nize her hallucination at a distance at
          which she could not perceive it with the
          naked eye In short the imaginary object
          which figures in the hallucination is per
          ceived under Hie same conditions as if It
          wero real Various other experiments
          are detailed in support of Ihis formula
          The operaglasses only act as if they are
          focused upon the point of hallucination
          through a prism the image is seen dnpli
          cated althouah the subject is absolutely
          ignoraut of the properties of a prism as
          well as of the fact that the glass is a
          prism The hypothesis favored by the
          authors to account for these and similar
          facts is that of the point of rediscove
          rs the imace beim
          associated with
          some slight detail of the white card
          when the suggestion was made such as a
          point or srain or other peculiarity of the
          surface imperceptible to the normal vis
          ion One of the most convincing argu
          ments in support of this hypothesis is the
          fact that a photograph of the plain white
          card used when the portrait was sug
          gested may be substituted and on being
          shown to the patient the hallucinatory
          image is seen just the same even two
          years after the original experiment and
          was done in one case
          SOME STRANGE PHENOMENA OK POLARITY
          are related The following experiments
          by MM Binet and Fore are given in illus
          tration We gave a patient in somnam
          bulism the common hallucination of a
          bird poised on her finger While she is
          caressing the imaginary bird she is
          awakened and a magnet is brought near
          her head After a few minutes she stops
          short raises her eyes and looks aiout in
          astonishment The bird which was on
          her linger has disappeared She looks
          all over the ward and at last finds It for
          we hear her say So you thought you
          would leave me little bird After a
          few minutes the bird disappears anew
          but almost immediately reappears The
          patient complains from time to time of
          pain in the head at a point corresponding
          to what has been described in this
          book as the visual center some
          distance above and slightly pos
          terior to the ear The mag
          net also has the same effect in suspending
          real perception One of the patients
          was shown a Chinese gong and striker
          and took fright on sight of the instrument
          When a blow was struck she instantly
          fell Into catalepsy She was reawakened
          and asked to look attentively at the
          gong meanwhile without her knowledge
          a small magnet was brought near her
          head Alter a minute the instrument had
          completely disappeared from her sight
          When it was struck with redoubled force
          she only looked from side to side with an
          air of slight astonishment In the case
          of a colored figure the magnet causes
          the patient to see the complementary
          color A red object whether real or
          suggested becomes green yellow be
          comes violet etc
          This book shows the positive methods
          now adopted by science in the treatment
          of this important subject Although
          hardly more than a beginning has yet
          been made in the exploration of its vast
          and intricate problems the foundations
          of the work are being laid in a most sub
          stantial manner What mysteries may
          vet be laid bare can hardly be con
          jectured At all events the results can
          not fail to have a great pathological
          value and it seems probable that
          with conditions once accurately estab
          liehedginestimable gains may be made
          in the treatment of disease particularly
          those disorders of a nervous or mental
          nature</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn93063557/1888-03-02/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=hypnosis+hypnotic+hypnotism+hypnotization+hypnotized</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Tcoplc fiuseeptlblo to JtypnntlMn.
          Pcrsons of n nervous constitution, nnd
          ln particular thoso subject to hysteria,
          nro most npt to fnll Into nrtiflciai Klcop.
          Thcro is thcn produccd in thein n pecu
          liar neurosis, hypnotism, having psjxhl
          cal nnd physical charactcra of its own a
          genuino disease prcscnting n diversity of
          Byinptoms. Hcnco hypnotic phenomena
          ouglit not to be callcd forth rnshly nor
          without the )recaution8 suggestcd by
          inedical scienco. 'VVomcn aro spccially
          Biiscoptiblo to hypnotio manipulation, par
          tictilarly during tho period bctwoen the
          18tlinnd tho 30th ycar, whcn tho ner
          vous system is in full nctivity. Young
          lncn may bo hypnotized, but it is very
          difllcult to produco hypnotic slccp in old
          uion or in ehildren. Pcrsons who in carly
          llfo nro subject to naturnl somnambulism
          or slecp walldng are latcr in life good
          hypnotio subjccts, just as they aro nlo
          likely to Imj victiius of hysteria and othcr
          nervous complaints.
          Jlany aro tlio processes oniploycd for
          prodticing hypnoais. One that is very
          frecjucntly used consists in fixing tiio gazo
          upon soino hriglit object placed a littlo
          abovo tho eycs and in front of tho median
          lino of tho forohcad, so that visunl fntiguo
          uiay cnsuo quickly, tiio eyeballs being
          dircctod upward and iuward. This pro
          cess, or othcrs of a liko kind, may Ihj otn
          ployed in tho caso of pcrsons wlio havo
          novcr bcforc been hypnotized. Dtit after
          awliile, when the subject has, so to speak,
          been eduoated. various nioro exix?ditious
          uiethods may be employed. Thus a jct
          of elcctrio light or a violcnt blow stmck
          on a gong near tlio ear of tho subject will
          quickly induco sleep. Again, in hypno
          tizablo ixji-sons, the surface of tlie body
          often prescnts special points, "hypnogenic
          zoncs, as thoy aro called, analagous to
          tho ''hysterogcuic zones." Simplo pres
          8uro upon theso produces hypnosis.
          Even in tho caso of tho most susceptiblo
          individuals rarely does sleep nppear when
          tliey. for tho flrst time, undergo tho hyp
          notizing manipulations, howcver skilled
          tho ojwrator may be. Tliero is necded a
          completo surrender of ono's will and nb
          senco of all mental preoccupation, and
          on tho part of the company prcsent abso
          lutc silcnce. In most cases exhibitions
          of hypnotization develop, at flrst, only
          vaguo jihcnomena not easily classified,
          foreshadowing, 60 to 6)eak, what will
          follow later. North American Eoview.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84037890/1888-07-25/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=hypnosis+hypnotic+Hypnotic+hypnotism+hypnotizing</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Study of the Hypnotic State.
          Dr. A. Dichas has mado n detailed study
          of tho memory In tho hypnotic state, nnd
          summarizes his main conclusions
          as follows: (1) during tlio hypnotic
          sleep tho subject remembers the experiences
          of his wiking Ufo ns well rs of
          previous hypnosis; (2) in hypnotism tlicro
          is often an exalt tion of tho memory, and
          at times n cliang in Its content, leading
          to tho assumpti n of a foreign
          (3) tho mo nory of what has been
          going on during hypnosis is usually lost,
          it can often bo ruvlvcd by n simplo suggestion,
          and at times the memory of a
          suggested hallucination may l!.,jor on.
          and influenco thu waking condition; (4)
          tho operator cau at his wjll havo any of
          tho nets of the liypnotK state remembered
          or forgotten by maMug this a part
          of tho suggestion; (5) sitgjfcstion seems to
          bo largely explicable 'as unconscious
          memory.
          Dr. Cybulski has studied tho power of
          hypnotic subjects to hypnotlzo themselves.
          IIo finds that such subjects
          strongly Imagiuo for a mlnuto or less that
          that tho operator commands them to go
          to sleep, nnd tho desired result ensues.
          Furthermore, If tlio subject, on going to
          sleep, imagines himself controlled by a
          certain person, then, even though another
          sent him to sleep, he will bo subject to
          tlio former, nnd not to tho operator.
          These observations show the Importance
          of tho subjectivo clement in tho process
          of hypnotism, nnd Indicate tho method by
          which tho subject unconsciously takes
          suggestions and acts upon them. Dr.
          Bcrkhan has applied hypnotism to the
          amelioration of the hearing of tho deaf.
          Ho tested tho hearing of nino deaf boys,
          and, after hypnotizing them, spoko to
          them and had varions.noises made before
          them Tho hearing of four of them was
          found to bo Improved, and tho improve
          merit is reported as still persisting after
          eighteen months Science.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1899-09-24/ed-1/?sp=21&amp;q=Hypnotic+HYPNOTISM+Hypnotism+Hypnotize+Hypnotized+medicine</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Hypnotism r
          Nothing. Then 1 will tell jou HOW YOU MAY LEARN HYPNOTISM.
          nil about It.
          I will show rou that It Is I am recognized aa the
          the tnout wotiilrrfnl leading Hypnotist InAmer
          tliltiR on rnrth. I will lea. 1 lint e practised and
          taught the Art of Hypnotism
          provo to on that Ilrpnottim
          cures diseasethat ItbanUhc tism for years. Nearly all
          pain that It unravels the mjrt- thechlcf Hypnotists of the
          lory of crimp that It aid Jus- land have been my pupils.
          ttco that It fosters brainpower No other Hypnotist has
          power ml tint It can bruucd won greater renown In this
          by all who know It to mnko those dear to them happy field or haa done so much
          nnd auccetif ul to reform the crrlnff and degraded and for the promotion of this
          to confer n thousand blessings on ttio feeble the un wonderful Science. 1 am
          happy the poverty-stricken on the unetlnp of mind the conceded authority on
          nnd body who arc al ays and everywhere a largo ele this subject In this coun
          ment In our surroundings. try. I have given the best of my days to tha study
          and demonstration of thin darling sclcnco. Its wonderful
          1 win ihow jou that every day la revealing new
          wonders deeper mysteries nnd wander possibilities derful powers and mysteries have become
          a part of
          In thin the Selrnco of the Century and that you my being and fill mo with an enthusiasm
          that over
          rnn learn to utlllie thin wonderful force In all Iti flows In the longing to Impart them
          to others. I nm
          form and phases. I will tell you about a wonderful like one who has found gold-mine and
          cannot keep
          Illumined book on Hypnotism which for the asking the secret of his wealth. All the
          plaudits I have won
          w HI conio to you postage paid without any charge or In my exhibitions and all the money I
          hm e made by
          cost whatever. But first you Ik them could not gratify mo half to much as to
          know that others were cherishing the snmo science
          WHAT IS HYPNOTISM and would further the development of Its possibili
          ties for good I want to Interest the whole world la
          Hypnotism Isaniipll or trance-like sleep i that one Hypnotism. I want you to learn It. 1
          want you to
          person by certain simple methods east orcr another. understand It because It will give you
          the mastery of
          while In thlsstatcthasubjectorhypn minds the ability to mould at pleasure the Impe
          oncan bo made to perform the most rial human will. Hypnotism will do n thousand
          urprlstnR and amazing feats bodily times more than this. It Is n healer of disease. It
          nnd mental of which they are totally .Isnwlnncrof human affections. It
          Incapable whtlo In their waking Isn spell of hnp. It Is an agency of
          hours. The mind of the subject Is success position wealth nnd fame.
          entirely under tlio control of the It Is n tutrncle. worker and an Influ
          operator. Ho may be made to see ence In all the ltal concerns
          and bcnr nnd think and feel exactly as the of Individuals families and so1 1
          Hypnotist wishes and just so long and no clety. Not to know such n
          longer 1 science Is to ho Ignorant Indeed
          Not to use. such a weapon 1st
          THE WONDERS OF HYPNOTISM. prcmo folly. It Is a\ntlabl
          to young or old of cither
          In attempting to stale what Hypnotism Is sex and It Is my proud
          I can gl\olntho space hero available but n boast to have made It
          bnro outline of Its tremendous powers. No
          pen could adcquatclydescrlbetheinarvclsihat FREE TO ALL.
          may bo bronght about through Hypnotism.
          You must sco It and learn to use It before I I have publfshed at great
          you can fully renllto how wonderful Is that eixpnnao n MA51-
          Nllout nnil mynterlouH force which en MOTII ir.i.us-
          ables one man to seize on Its very throne the TKATljn TK15AT-
          will of another and'mako him conform to his IHF. or limtriirtor
          Bllgbtest wish In every act and feeling. In llypnotlamwhlcli
          tein ovcrythlnir
          THE USE OF HYPNOTISM. te about this Art. A
          copy of It Is at your
          The possession of Hypnotic power will open _ eervlca If you tnko
          up to you whole regions of good to your fellow mor the trouble to write for It.
          tals and a sure way for yourself to honors and wealth There Is positively no cost nor
          charge In connection
          no less than to scientific progress and pleasant pas- with this gift. If you wrlto for It
          oven on a postal
          time. If you are an eager student It will unfold to card 1 will send It promptly nnd free
          by mall. Kv-
          you a now and fascinating realm of science. If you eryhodv who has read It pronounces It a
          wonderful
          are a person of means and book. It Is a clear exposition of the Importance
          S leisure Itwlll provide you with methods wonders and uses of Hypnotic Sclcncn
          v endless recreation. If you are down even to the details of entertainments given
          generous and philanthropic for money-making purposes. Never before \\ai
          \Itwlllcnablcyoutuheapblcsi- such a gift made In the Interests of any science.
          lIngs on less fortunate fellow-
          j beings. If you are the head THIS WONDERFUL BOOK IS FREE.
          j will of a make family or household. It It Is the most valuable and Interesting work of
          the
          nnd you the physician kind ever published. It explains the Mysteries or
          true ot
          comforter those
          lu Hypnotism from A to Z. It tells you Just what Hyp
          your that caro. And finally notism Is and what It will accomplish. It tells you
          suppose ago or fortune how you may control the minds of others perform ns-
          arc frowning upon you or that tonlimng feats and produce amusement by the hour.
          you arestlllyoung.fortuneless It covers the whole ground of Hypnntlo methods In
          and and have
          friendless to
          yet caryo In
          your way
          such that ou can learn rapidly. It tells you
          away
          the world all these various privileges will be In
          your
          all should know about Hypnotism Its phenomena
          and with them you
          grasp along a sure means to position
          na Its mysteries and Its advantages to you personally
          Influence happiness and golden wealth. If
          your
          wealth. Influence
          for the certain attainment of
          ally
          choice Is not already taken or desire to make
          you a
          cannot fiord to bo without
          health and happiness. Ton n
          change can also 11 ml In Hypnotism Itself lu-
          you a
          and honorable out this knowledge. You need not alt In darkncsa
          crtithe. tbat
          permiinant profession while such light Is free. Do sensible send for a copy
          will give you fame and competence during your active
          of this book and Icnrn to Hypnotize.
          with and
          tive years security distinction for the
          evening ot life.
          HYPNOTISM IN DISEASE.
          Hypnotism has Indeed grand and glorious utili
          ties It has gains aa well as enjoyments for all who
          master It. Among these the
          place of honor limy well bo
          1 plven to Us wonderful efficacy
          llu alleviating human gutter-
          ling and curing disease. With-
          lout doubt It la the Krcat
          Ihcnlorof the future. No
          /Anodyne ever known Is equal
          f to It In the relief and allcvl-
          r atton of pain. No medicine
          ever prepared can wrestle so
          effectively with the ravages of
          disease. The delicate and nervous
          vous woman tbo overworked
          man and the sickly and fretful child may all alike be
          benefited by Its application. It Ii a boon and bless
          ing to the entire race.
          AS A MEANS OF AMUSEMENT.
          The fun makln possibilities of Hypnotism are
          Imply unlimited. Ha\o you over been present at
          an exhibition ot Hypnotism given cither to a publto
          or private audience If you have you will readily
          agree that as a means of entertainment of genuine
          hilarity and fun this wonderful power Is beyond all
          rivalry. Not all the comedy ever teen on the mimic
          stage Is so absurd and mirth-provoking or so full of
          laughable and yet harmless surprises.
          The absurd and ridiculous things a Hypnotized
          person will do are almost beyond belief Uo will do
          anything you command or ftuRgcst to him.
          A f uw persons wlillo under the Influence of Hypno
          tism will produce more genuine amusement moro
          astonishment and amazement than a minstrel show
          and comic openi combined. This crand work contains hundreds or tbo most ar
          This fact will at once tistic Illustrations ever produced. Tlio cover Is n
          suggest that If you have no remarkable work of art. Above all clto the subject
          accomplishments Hypno- matter Is ably handled and Is new llcly and fascin
          tlsm would provo of Im ating. Everything Is told In plain lanijunRO Kvcry
          mense value to you. You fact method and phenomenon described can lie un
          would no longer ho kept derstood by anybody who knows how to read. Kvcry
          In the background at a par process that calls for pictorial help will bo found
          ty or publlu gathering for fully Illustrated so that you will bo carried along
          with the abfilty to llyp- pleasantly until you know all the Ins and outs of tlio
          notlze you can produce subject. Everything about the work shows that no
          amusement for hours at a expense was spared In getting It up and when you
          time. With a few subjects consider tbat It
          or even one you can keep _ COSTS ABSOLUTELY NOTHING
          an audience lu a continual roar of laughter.
          you must admit that this Is tha most generous offer
          YOU CAN LEARN IT. uvcr made lu behalf of this marvelous science.
          Let me mail you a copy of tuU book. If you nro
          Reader you can become a Hypnotist. There Is no not surprised auddcllRhted with It If you
          do no t con-
          reason on earth to the contrary. It is a faculty Inborn elder It tlio most valuable and
          Interesting Rift ever
          born In every Individual just like the faculty of offered the American public I will
          Rladly reimburse
          speech. It only requires cultivation In order to bo you for the slight trouble of wrltlnc
          for It. Hcincm-
          developed and applied. In fact. It Is as easy to learn herltls free as nlr. A postal card
          will bring It by
          how to Hypnotize aa It Is to learn how to waltz or return mallpostage paid. Bend for It
          today. Address
          PROF L A HABRADEN Dept N Jackson</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042405/1892-12-15/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=hypnosis+Hypnosis+hypnotic+Hypnotic+hypnotism+HYPNOTISM+hypnotized+hypnotizing</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THE ABUSE OF HYPNOTISM.
          Quack* and CliarlntaiM Wlio Mukti I'M OL
          It to iiull the Public.
          Wliilo tho benefits from hypnotism
          thus fur have been few anil small, the
          evils have been many nml great. Its
          Bleeplike btato is not a normal sleep,
          bringing health and Htrength to the
          sliuuberer, but a morbid conditiou bor­
          dering u|iou disease. It irritates the en­
          tire nervous organization and tempora­
          rily if not organically weakens the sys­
          tem. This drawback is serious enough.
          Darker and more terrible effects lie in
          the suppression of the object's will for
          the time being, and the substitution
          therefor of the operator's. In this re­
          gard it opens avenues to crime and crimi­
          nals such us has never been equaled
          heretofore. Already so many discredit­
          able actions, not to use a stronger word,
          have been committed in Europe by
          means of hypnotism that in Italy, Aus
          tro-Hungary, parts of Switzerland, Co­
          penhagen and other municipalities laws
          have been enacted prohibiting its public
          practice by any except physicians. So,
          on the other hand, tip police, without
          any statute on the subject, have treated
          traveling mesmerists as disorderly char­
          acters. Thus Donato was expelled from
          Italy, and Hansen, another hypnotist,
          from Austria, was notified never to re­
          turn under penalty of arrest, fine and
          imprisonment.
          This Donato (whose real name, by the
          way, is Dhont) hypnotized an Italian ar­
          tillery officer, who immediately became
          half crazy. From time to time he would
          go into somnambulism at the sight of a
          bright object. He would follow carriage
          iamps. and unless prevented would walk
          toward locomotive or steamer lights.
          An architectural student was mesmer­
          ized by staring at his compasses, after
          which it was impossible for him to draw
          without going to sleep.
          A young girl of Milan, of beauty and
          character, was hypnotized and impressed
          with the notion that she was married 'o
          a man she had never seen but once, and
          then in the darkness. She went crazy
          and died in a hospital.
          Another voting girl (of Paris, this
          time) was put under a similar spell and
          was ruined. She finally entered the
          Saltpetriere hospital, where, after along
          and painful remedy, what was left of
          her former self was pronounced cured.
          In New York a hypnotized person was
          made to believe that he had taken slow
          poison. He fell sick and wasted away
          to a shadow. Not until the attending
          physician discovered the true nature of
          the hallucination and relivpnotized the
          subject was there any symptom of con­
          valescence.
          In Turin, at a series of hypnotic lec­
          tures and public experiments, a large
          proportion of those who attended were
          taken sick with headache, insomnia and
          other nervous ailments. A few of those
          who were of a hysterical temperament
          remained ill for along time.
          In the foregoing cases the hypnotizing
          was done with no evil intent, but there
          are hundreds of recorded instances where
          it was done with intent of evil.—Phila­
          delphia Times.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1894-12-16/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Hypnosis+hypnosis+hypnotic+Hypnotic+hypnotically+Hypnotism+hypnotism+hypnotize+Hypnotized+hypnotized+hypnotizing</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Hypnotism and Its Relation to Crime. None are more bigoted than infidels. The science
          of a generation ago was proud of its infidelity. Without a dem onstration in (acts it
          would believe nothing; nor, indeed, beyond its nar row physical range did it desire to see
          anything, to know anything:. No Span ish padre in Mm train of Isabella, no exhorting
          captain of Cromwell's pray erful warriors, no hadji at the well of Zem-Zem, was ever
          blinder to enlight enment, more invincible to argument. In the opinion of tnia scientific
          omnis cience, astrology, witchcraft, magic, omens, premonitions, spiritualism, clair
          voyance, mesmerism, personal magnet ism and ghosts were alike ridiculous and incredible.
          These alleged phenom ena could not be brought under the microscope nor submitted to the
          rule of three. They were therefore impossible in both the English and the French sense of
          the word. This arrogant, bigoted devotion to the purely physical exhibited none of the
          lofty ideality of that pure, if uninstructed, soul who exciated "I believe it, because it
          is impossible!" These scientists were "of the earth, earthy." 1 test limit Truth could
          not, however, lone endure this degradation. The things undreamt of by iiuratio existed
          nevvriliuless. They will always exist: nor will ignoring them obliterate them. Science
          accused Religion of believing too much, but Science herself believed too little. To fall
          by dark into a ditch and believe it a well may not be sensi ble; to ignore that you are in
          the ditch because you cannot see it, is scarcely iiiur« reasonable. The rebound of this
          great intellectual movement has, perhaps, already «oue too far. We have become as fond of
          mysteries as a priest of Thebes. We believe all that our grandfathers be lieved, and much
          that those venerable men would have ridiculed. As childreu around the dying tire, we must
          have our tfliost storius before we sleep. Solemn London editors gravely describe the
          mysterious pictures that present them selves in a ball of crystal to the eyes of the
          editors' female friends. The editors themselves cannot see these pictures, but, of course,
          they exist. Nobody would deny that. Thought transference is an established fact. The young
          man reflects uitrhtly upon the superexcel ieuce of his fiancee, and he is sure that Marie
          smiles responsive in her dreams. The virtues of faith cure are self-evi dent. Only beliova
          that the forceps are made of sponge, and you will never know when the tooth is cut. But
          the greatest of these new beliefs is hypnotism. Its growth bids tair to divide the nation.
          From recent events it would seem that some Democrats have already disappeared, and soon
          there will be no Republicans. The "iniquitous doctrines" of the Hypnotiz ers will be
          assailed ore long la the na tioual platform of the Hypnotized. Everywhere intrudes the
          hypnotic "suggestion." We may think we paid a delicate compliment to the rector, but tii c
          wife of our bosom put it into our head. Little Reginald was "thinkin' of them Christmas
          presents rigbtalong." But to th« criminal, the condemned of man, comes the new doctrine as
          a heavenly aid. The glories of iisanity are past. It is not now conceded that Mr. Brown,
          of i'psilanti, who killed his neighbor Rogers, should be at once dis charged because th«
          town records of Boston recall the incarceration of an ancestral Brown "forasmuch as lie
          was distraught of his intellects." The new method is much simpler, much easier. The
          cashier robs a great bank systematically for years. He was perfectly honest himself, but
          was under the control of another man, who got most of the money. A scoundrel slays an
          innocent woman through a hired as sassin. The actual murderer had the best intentions, but
          he cou'd not help adopting the elaborate plan proposed by the hypnotizing villain. The
          plan was known to intelligent men, but they were "hypnotized," and could no.t warn the
          victim. Various girls elope with mar ried men, but they are "model young ladies" under
          hypnotic influence. If all these things are true, anarchy is already upon us. bins Sins
          and J oliet are our proper universities. Matters, however, might be exaggerated—by the
          other newspapers. A late inquiry among prominent local representatives of tho medical and
          legal professions has been most reassuring. The following com munications exhibit the true
          nature of hypnotism and its possible relations to crime. The articles set forth the most
          recent and approved views upon a dif ficult and complicated subject, and ex emplify the
          heights to which have risen the sciences of Galen and Triboniau, PROF. W. XAVIER SUDDUTH.
          University of Minnesota. In answer to your letter of inquiry re garding the relation of
          hypnosis to crime, would say that 1 no not consider that there is any relation, and in
          proof it my position cite the fact that hypno tism is as old as man and has been known as
          far back as Biblical record goes- The Egyptians also were familiar with it, and so have
          been all modern nations; but in all this time, so far a3 my knowledge extends, there has
          not been a single well-authenticated case on the criminal records of any country where
          hypnosis has been used to coiu del any one to commit any crime, not a single case where a
          pre viously virtuous woman hns been led from the path of virtue, nor any individual
          swindled out of money by means of hypnotic sugges tion, nor do I believe there ever will
          be. Hypnosis is not a condition like ether or chloroform narcosis, but a mental state into
          which the individual volun tarily enters. No one can be hypno tised against his will, nor
          be kept in the hypnotic state any longer than he is willing to be. The Idea that many per
          sons have that only weak-minded people can be hypnotized is entirely false. The best
          subjects I have ever had have been this best educated and possessed of the strongest
          wills. All that is necessary for such people to do In order to become subjects is to
          desire to \\ierience the sensation and put themselves in a stale of absolute passivity.
          Idiots, insane people and skeptics can not be hypnotized. In order to be a good subject a
          person must first be will ing—he must have will power sufficient to will to do as he is
          told, and last, but not least, be must possess faith in the operator. Mo one can bo
          hypnotized who do.-s not know that he is going to be. The process is purely one of
          suggestion. There is no mysterious fluid that passes from one individual to the other.
          Neither is it a condition of paralysis, in which the individual is unable to resist the
          will of the operator. The suggestion of acts to a person in the hypnotic state that are
          contrary to his ideas of right and wrong will always meet with failure, and if the sugges
          tion is persisted in will cause the indi vidual to awaken. Constant repetition may, as iv
          the waking state, educate him iv the premises, but a person iv the hypnotic state is less
          susceptible to criminal suggestion than ho wuuhl be in the waking condition, for th»
          reason that in the hypnotic state nil sense of material relations is set aside for tho'
          time being. The personality of the in dividual la not, however, materially al tered, only
          Modified, partially domi nated hy the will ol another for the time being, but only in so
          far as his own ideas of rieht and wrong are not seri ously crossed. Any strong countor
          cturent of ideas will break the relation ship nnd arouse him from the. hypnotic state.
          Furthermore, there must be a condi tion of absolute sympathy and confi dence presented in
          order to secure' the best results. Faith in the ability and' good intentions of the
          operator is an 'es- 1 Mattel element in hypnotism. No sane person would go to sleep with a
          burglar under his bed if he knew it, neither would he permit a rascal to hypnotize him.
          The sensational stories that go the rounds of cheap literature regarding theft, arson and
          murder committed in the hypnotic state, by reason of that state, are the creations of
          diseased minds. Unless a person is a thief or murderer at heart, he can no more be made
          one in the hypnotic than he can in the waking state, in considering this subject, however,
          it must b» remem bered that there are people in the world who are negatively virtuous and
          gener ally well behaved—people who are good simply because they have never been tempted to
          be bad. Such persons, tempted either in the waking or hyp notic state, might or would fall
          simply because they have no In dwelling force of character. Such people are only safe in a
          cloister or be liir.a prison bars, and there, in my esti mation, is where a considerable
          portion of the inhabitants of a village in a neighboring state should be placed. If wo can
          believe the accounts in the papers, an innocent man is being perse cuted at the
          Instigation of two hysterical girls who have the power of throwing themselves into the
          trance state. The days of Salem witchcraft are being en acted over again. 1 have never
          seen anything yet in my fifteen years' study of the subject that has led me to believe in
          telepathy, and I fully concur in the opinion of Judge Bailey as to the ad mission of
          •'hypnotically" secured testi mony in court. The basis of hypnotism is suggestion, and
          this may be given in the waking as well as the hypnotic state, and need not be by word
          alone. Anything that stands for an idea to the mind of the indi vidual is sufficient to
          produce the effect. Suggestions in the waking state sometimes produce epidem ics, as in
          the middle ages, when men, women and children were carried away by the miliion with the
          idea of of rescuing the Holy city. Epidemics of crime seem to spring up as the result of
          some dastardly deed as the incentive. "Lynching bees" follow each other in rapid
          succession. Train robberies go in groups, although widely separated geographically. To
          sucii an extent do these things occur that sometimes .it seems as if people were ere
          atures «f im pulse and suggestion rather than rea soning beings. The danger in hypnosis
          lies in its abuse, and not in its use. Every power has its good and its bad aspect, and so
          has this one; but hypnosis offers its own remedy. If, when abused,* hypnosis may weaken
          the will,even as morphine, ether, chloral and all other narcotics, rt may also be used to
          strengthen the will again, whereas'the other analgesics can not. No one has ever diod from
          hyp nosis used as an aosesthetic, while hundreds have died under chloroform. My prediction
          is that, when the atmos phere has been cleared of supersti tion, bigotry and professional
          jealousy, hypnosis will come into general use as an analgesic and anaesthetic To inhibit
          or even limit the use of this potent remedy for the relief of pain would be an outrage
          upon the community. Far better educate the people up to its right use and point out the
          danger of its abuse. If it is to be controlled by legislation, where will the line be
          drawn? Let me cite a few places where it is now used. A little child is playing with Its
          blocks or dollies, aud the nurse enters to put the little one into its crib for its
          regular afternoon nap. The child does not feel sleepy, but insists on being allowed to
          finish the house he is building, but the nurse persists, and by blandishment* and promises
          ot sugar plums finally succeeds in tretting the child into its crib or into her lap, and
          then begins the monotonous motion of rocking it to sleep, meanwhile emphasizing the
          suggestion by the low droning of the lullaby song accompanied by the com maud: "Go to
          sleep, darling—go to sieep sleep sleep"—and the child "iocs" to sleep—hypnotized. Again, a
          child at its play In some way hurts its finger, and runs to mamma, crying: the moth er
          soothes away the pain by ca resses and diversion of the attention, and in all probability,
          if injury is con siderable, ending by rocking and sing intr it to sleep while the tears
          yet glis ten between its closed lids. In yonder darkened chamber lies a person suffering
          from that terribly painful affliction —"a sick head ache"—the slightest jar giving ex
          cruciating agony, such as is to be appreciated only by one who has had it. A friend,
          hearing of the case, comes in, and by gently stroking the fevered brow soon quiets the
          throbbing pulse and puts the sufferer to aleep, to awake entirely free from pain. A person
          suffuringifrom an acute neu ralgia, caused an by exposed pulp in a de cayed tooth, calls
          upon me at my house in the evening. I apply some simple house hold remedy, and, by a tew
          gentle but firm passes over the face in the painful region, suggest freedom from pain, and
          send the sufferer home to pass a com fortable night in sleep, instead of walk ing the
          floor, as many a person has done. A prominent man, whose voice, no doubt, will be heard in
          the halls ot our legislature the coming winter on this subject, if it comes up, recently
          went to a "painless joint" and had twoachiiur teeth removed with odontuader, or something
          of a like nature, and after wards suffered intense neuralgia. He Bought me at my home just
          at dinner time. 1 applied topical remedies, but failed to relieve him. I finally suggested
          hypnosis, and, placing him upon a lounge in my study, soon had him asleep, and left him to
          rest until 1 could tret my dinner. On returning I found him awake, the pain having oeen
          stronger than my au^estiou to sleep I again hypnotized him, and remained with him, finally
          securing immunity from the neuralgia, and sent him home to a quiet night's rest, a firm
          believer hi the efficacy of hypnosis as an anal* gesic. A lady came to the late clinic at
          the university with a tumor of long standing, the removal of which had been a constant
          dread, undermining her health and inducing morbid nerv ous symptom*. The tumor was
          successfully removed under hyp nosis, and the patient subsequently treated for her
          nervousness.with marked improvement and promise of final cure A woman stiffenmk from a
          known heart lesion, who had permitted her teeth to decay to the jjum line tHjcauso an
          anesthetic had been inteudicted by hei family physician, presented for treatment. She
          proved a Kd subject, and had a lance number of badly dis~ eased teeth and roots removed
          under hypnosis, waking up vvitli a smile on her face, having been perfectly obliv ious to
          auy paiu, and remained free from any subsequent bad effects of neu ralgia or shock. A man
          suffering from hysterio-eri lepsy of several years' standing presented for treatment.
          Suppur ation of the antrum and frontal sinuses was diagnosed, and, as these cases
          coutraindicate the ordinary an aesthetics, hypnosis wan used in the presence of several
          physicians with absolute success and tubes placed in the several sinuses. The operation
          was followed np by the use of suggestion in the treatment of the epileptic attacks, and,
          although the case is still under treatment, every indication points to a cuie. The
          epileptic seizures are under full control, and all internal Medication has been dropped
          these many days. A woman in the fifth month of a "vomiting pregnancy," with other serious
          complications, wasted to a shadow, and only existing on three quarters ot a grain of
          morphine daily, administered hypodermatically, was put under hypnotic control, and the
          morphine stopped at the second sitting. At the third site was taught to hypnotize herself.
          The vomiting was treated L*y suggestion, as well as some other annoying complications, and
          the patient remains to this day, nearly one month since the first treatment, free from the
          use of morphine, a"iid doing as well as .could be expected of one iv her condition. A
          large number of stammerers have also come under my treatment, with varying decrees of
          success; none, however, witnout improvement, and several have been dismissed as cured. In
          the licht ot tlie above expe rience, of which the cases cited are only examples, is it
          strange that I should be a firm believer in hypnosis as an anal tesie and an aim-schetic
          in the treat ment of neuralgia? The following clippiug from the New York Evening Post very
          clearly sets forth the present status of hypnosis in its relation to med icine: The extent
          to which therapeutic experi ments in hypnotic suggestion are exciting the attention of
          physicians and awakening the interest of the general public may be in ferred from the fact
          that during: the past year more than 100 books and brochures, especially devoted to the
          discussion of this subject, have been published. One of the most valuable of these is the
          small volume just issued by Bong, in Berlin, entitled "Die Bedeutuug der Uynotischen
          Suggestion als Ileilmittel." The author. Dr. J. Grossman, editor of the Zeitschrift fur
          Hypotismus, prints communications from thirty of the most eminent professors and
          physicians ot Europe, firing the results of their experi ence in the application of
          hypnotic sugges tions to the healing of disease. Thus Van .'edeu and Van Reuterghem. of
          Amsterdam, report that from May 5,1557, to June 30, 1893, in the institution under their
          charge, 1.098 patients were subjected to the treatment; of those £8.28 percent were
          entirely cured. 26!) per cent permanently improved, 21.02 per cent slightly bettered,
          17.81 per cent unaffected, and in U.lB per cent of the cases the results were unknown. Dr.
          Wetterstrand, of Stockholm, has used this method of medical treatment in 7,000, and Dr.
          Bornneim, of Nancy, in 12,000 cases, and both express themselves strongly in favor of it.
          Indeed, Dr. Bernheim does not hesitate to declare that the study of Hypnotic sugges tion
          should be made obligatory in all medical school?, and that nowadays a physician who
          ignores the psychical element in disease, and has no knowledge of the part it plays in
          palhogeny and therapeutics, is no better than a horse doctor, and should confine him self
          to veterinary practice. Another impor tant point brought out by Dr. Kraltt-Ebing, of
          Vienna, is the influence of "a utosugges tion" in the production of disease. The number of
          ailments and morbid conditions of this) kind, that have their origin in the nervous
          system, and are indicated by pains, paralysis and other symptoms of hysterical,
          hypochondriac and neurasthenic affections, is astonishing. Although not merely i mag inary
          complaints, they cease with the re moval of the "autosuargestive cause," which may be
          effected by any change of scene ban ishing it from the thoughts, or by heterosug gestion
          (fremd-suggestlon) on the part of a physician, who may impart it verbally or in the
          disguise of a dose of medicine. In obsti nate cases, in which the autosuggestion is firmly
          entrenched in mental imbecility, su perstituiion, morbid appetites and passions,
          inveterate habits, or abnormities of charac ter, recourse must be had to hypnotism. That
          the great majority of mankind are capable of being hypnotized is shown by the experi ments
          of Dr. Freihorr yon Schrank Noizing, of Munich, on 5.705 persons of different na
          tionalities, of whom only per cent proved to be entirely unsusceptible." The following
          paragraph is taken from a letter of mine published in the Minneapolis Journal: "I have
          observed from a perusal of the literature on the- sub ject that nearly al! the work done
          so far has been in the direction of investigating its value as a therapeutic agent, rather
          than as au an a-sthetie. Tiie special line of work that I have been and am still engaged
          upon is its application to sur gery, upon which little or nothing has been written. The
          value of hypnosis as an anal gesic in neuralgia has long been known. That I entered uuon
          the work with consid erable trepidation is shown by the fact that, although I have been a
          close student of the subject formauy years past, aud have uieJ it in my private practice,
          yet I bad never given a public demonstration until last year. I cannot do belter in
          closing this letter than to quote the opening paragraph of the first paper I ever wrote
          upon the subject: "The liae of detnarkaiiou between the sublime aud the ridiculous,
          between the mysterious ana the miraculous, Between belief and iucredu l.ty, between
          respect and diversion in this life, is so narrow that to espouse auy causa that is not
          woll understood, or in at verges on tne occult, is really dangerous to oue's reputa tion;
          and la treating of hypnosis I should be vain Indeed did did I expect to escape the lot of
          others who have iv the past essayed the role of interpreters of ibis ruueh-abused, but
          Httle understood, science.' 1 The clinic at the -U." while ruuulng. daily demon strated
          its value as au amesthetic. It was fitting that a dental clinic stiould bo the first 10
          take the lead in the maUor, us dentistry has always b'en in the front rank iv ex peri meiu
          with aiuesthetics, and with excellent results.' 1 I As to who can use hypnosis there is no
          limit. All are more or less suscepti ble to its influence. All that the hyp notizer can do
          is to direct the course to be pursued,and the result depends upon the Individual. I have
          taught a great many persons to hypnotize themselves, to their great benefit. When it is
          fully understood that it is a mental state and not a physical condition, ana that no one
          can bo hypnotized against his will, then tho dread that some good pcoDle have of it will
          cease, and hypnotic sug gestion will come to occupy th place it deservedly should among
          household remedies. _ Call and see what George Refer, Ml Wubasha street, has to offer in
          Pure Wines for the holidays. HON. C. D. O'BRIEN. As to whether the law recognizes an
          alleged hypnotic influence, under which a crime was committed, as being a de fense fur the
          party charged with the commission of such crime, 1 will say that, so far as the existence
          of the con dition called hypnotism is concerned, or whether it exists as a condition or as
          a fact. lam unable to state. From what is said about it ami written about it, it aDpears
          that some people have the fac ulty of producing on others an influ ence called hysterical
          or hypnotic, un der which the subject apparently ap pears to have abandoned all self-power
          and self-consciousness, and to be en tirely under the domination of the op erator. But so
          far the law has nol, recognized the existence of any such condition; that is, it has not
          been satisfactorily proven ift any court of justice, to my knowledge, that either tbe
          operator possesses the alleged power, or that the subject can be entirely subordinated to
          the will of the operator to the extent that it is claimed that he can—that is, so as to
          produce an abnormal condition in which the individuality of the subject is completely
          wiped out, and he or she be comes the more instrument of the de sires or wishes of the
          operator. Now, I say the law does not recognize the existence of that condition; there
          fore, up to this time, there is, so far as 1 know, no adjudicated case which holds that a
          defense based upon a theory that a criminal act was committed by one because of and while
          under the power of hypnotic influence can be sustained. I very much doubt whether such a
          de fense ever will b« sustained, because I do not tluiik the law will ever recogniz a
          hypnotic condition as a defense to a criminal act committed by one who claims to be in
          that state when so committing the crime. Neither would the law recognize, without a direct
          statutory enactment in that behalf, a criminal act committed by the operator in the
          hypnotic suggestion. In other words, to make it plain, if it should be claimed that the
          operator hypnotized the subject, and then, while the subject was under the influence,
          suggested to the subject the commission of a crime, which such person so under the
          influence should then proceed to commit, the legal consequences would be, very likely,
          that both of them would be indicted for the crime and both Dunislied as principal and
          accessory both before and after the fact. You now ask me whether the hypno tizing of a
          person against his will, winch results in the mental or physical injury of the person so
          hypnotized, would be considered in law a crime. Under the penal code of this state there
          is no provision that will reach such a e.ise that lam aware of. As this state has
          abolished common law jurisdiction for crimes, and nothing is a crime unless so
          specifically designated iv the statutes (and we have no statute upon the sub ject of
          hypnotism or occult Influence), there could be no charge predicated upon the hypnotizing
          of an individual, pro vided the subject consented to the ex periment; but if it should be
          proved iv court that such a thing as hypnotic in fluence existed, and that a person was
          hypnotized against his will, thereby producing a physical injury to him, 1 should think
          that certainly, under the common law jurisdiction, and, perhaps, under our penal code, a
          prosecution for assault might be maintained, for it has been held that the administration
          of anesthetics to a patient against his will do's constitute an assault. Speaking
          generally of the subject, the most remarkable thing connected with the so-called hypnotic
          manifestations is the resemblance which they bear to the old theories of witchcraft, both
          in Eu rope and iv this country. The alleged case of hypnotism re cently occurring in Eau
          Claire, and the manifestations of the hypnotic subjects, as reported in the Globs on last
          Sun day, are remarkably similar to the man ifestations of witchcraft delusion as we read
          them, both in the histories of Eu rope and of New England. The state ments of the two
          girls in Eau Claire concerning the Influence of Jr. Pickin, and the hysterical or
          cataleptic con dition which they ascribe to his in fluence, are almost precisely the same
          as the manifestations of witchcraft aud the charges made against those unfor tunate people
          that are alleged to have practiced the art In New England dur ii.sr the early history of
          the country. When you add to this the sympathetic symptoms between the two s-irls, you
          have, if you choose to call it so, a case of witchcraft or possession produced by
          witchcraft, or absolutely similar symp toms; and it is a very remarkable thing that in
          tiie year 18U4, at what we consider the acme of our development in civili zation, progress
          and culture, we should find ourselves confronted with a condi tion, or popular delusion,
          which has heretofore been entirely ascribed to the ignorance and superstition of former
          ages. You ask me if a confession or testi mony obtained under hypnotic Influence could be
          used in a court of law, or would the procuring of a confession under surh circumstances be
          a violation of personal right. The entire value of a confession rests upon the
          eireumstamces under which it is obtained. It must be volun tary, and not induced by undue
          influence of any kind. The mind of the party confessing must not be overcome Liy any
          influence such as threats, or hope of re ward or of escaping punishment. It therefore
          follows that a confession obtained from a person who, it is conceded, was at the time
          unable to contiol his own faculties, would be worthless, nor would a person under what is
          called hypnotic influence be permitted to testify in a court of com mon law while in that
          condition, if such condition were known to the court. 11 a person BeSerinf under temporary
          or permanent aberration of mind is dis qualified as a witness, so would a per son be who
          waa under the influence either of narcotics or intoxicants to such an extent as to atlect
          his judgment. If you once assume that a person can be placed under hypnotic influence and
          the law should recognize it, it would cer tainly disqualify that person from testi fying
          while in that condition. HON. CHARLES E. FLANDRAU. On the subject of hypnotism 1 know
          nothing, and do not suppose any one knows any more than I do, therefore 1 will say nothing
          about it. As to whether the plea of having been under hypnotic influence at tho time of
          the commission of a crime would be re ceived by a court as a defense, all I can say is to
          Quote a very familiar principle in criminal law, winch is that intention is Mm gist of oil
          crime. No ohm can be guilty of a crime unless lie perpetrated it knowingly. Responsibility
          for ciime depends wholly upon intention. A familiar instance of this principle i is the.
          plea of insanity, if the party is insane when the act is committed, he is not himself, is
          not impelled b\ his own i reason, but by some delusion thai clouds bn mind and destroys
          his will. .So he j is not held responsible for his act. If any one person possesses the
          power of absolutely controlling the actions of another (which [seriously doubt, unless
          such other is so mentally diseased as to be generally irresponsible), and should by such
          influence and power impel such person to commit a crime. tii«?n, of course, the one
          exerting the influence would be the criminal, and not the party performing the involuntary
          act. This is on the principle that he acted without intention on hi* part, but by an irre
          sistible impulse exerted by another. Whether courts will accept any ex pert evidence on a
          matter of this kind. 1, of course, am unable to say; but. in the light of experience,
          science and common sense, I think they should be very careful In listening to anything of
          the kind. Charles E. Flasdkau. DR. W. E. HALLOWELL. A great deal of nonsense has been
          printed in the daily press lately about hypnotism, «nd people generally seem willing to
          set hardly any limit to the powers of the dreadful individuals who "influence," in
          accordance with their own sweet will, any and everybody with whom they come into contact,
          and be fore whom neither virtue, life nor prop erty is supposed to be safe. If one may
          judge by the tone of the press in the :.ews and editorial eolutnus,an epidemic of hypnotic
          crime is threatening the in-</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1896-08-22/ed-1/?sp=19&amp;q=Hypnosis+HYPNOSIS+hypnosis+hypnot+hypnotic+Hypnotic+hypnotism+hypnotized+hypnotize</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>HYPNOSIS MACHINES
          Devices to Produce the M umrne
          8tate Mechanicaly.
          "Ill' ERB AD CM lTtm
          Influence of Certain Chemicals
          Upon Sensitive Subjects.
          USES OF THE POWER
          VEN HYPNOSIS
          may now be pro
          duced by machinery.
          We are approaching
          a day when the di
          rect influence of
          Svengalles will not
          be necessary to
          throw Trilbies Into
          subjective at ate a.
          when hypnotists will
          exert their powers
          through machinery
          set to operate at
          given times, the
          presence of the Instruments being un
          known to the subjects. The mechanical
          mesmerizer will then find an essential
          place In the burglar's tool kit, and we will
          have to look under our beds to see If such
          traps have been set by our enemies. The
          mechanical hypnotizer as now made, how
          ever, is strictly a scientific instrument.
          The government's bureau of education re
          cently purchased a collection of such appar
          atus, which are new In this country. They
          will be used by a specialist for studying
          the values of hypnotic suggestion in the
          education of the abnormal classes. Ex
          periments will be made determining their
          effect upon the sensibilities, emotions,
          breathing,. circulation and temperature of
          the body'.
          An Elaborate Apparatus.
          The most elaborate form of hypnotiser
          is a small box, containing clock work, sur
          mounted by two horizontal oblong fans,
          one over the other, revolving rapidly In op
          posite directions. The fans are studded
          on each side with a row of circular mir
          rors, about the size of nickel pieces. The
          rapid rotation produces an odd flashing
          effect which greatly fatigues the eyelid
          muscles of the beholder. This machine is
          found to be very effective when used upon
          sersitives who can be thrown into a hyp
          notic sleep by concentration or sight stimu
          lus.
          A simpler form of mechanical hypnotizer
          is a belt of broad tape to be placed upon
          the forehead and over the temples, being
          tied at the back of the head. From a me
          tallic plate In front protrudes a wire, ex
          terding upward In an S-like curve and
          holding a bright ball of nickel, about the
          size of a marble, at the end. When this is
          placed upon the st'bject the wire Is bent
          until the ball reaches a point above the
          eye, where it may be seen by the wearer
          only by intensely straining the eyelids.
          The same effect, as produced by the former
          rr achine is accomplished by this simpler ap
          paratus. These instruments have been
          Irvented to serve in substitution for the
          gestures, known as passes, commonly ma
          by hypnotists. The scientific hypnotist
          makes movements before and above tho
          eyes of his subject to concentrate his at
          tention and to fatigue the eyelid muscles
          both by causing the eyes to follow the
          movements and by fannirig air against
          them. Fatigue of the muscles of the eye
          lids is found to he one of the direct causes
          of sleep. Persons in no mental need of sleep
          may "read themselves sleepy" under a too
          bright or a too im light. A severe breeze
          against the eyelids will cause the same
          effect.
          Magnetic Influentea.
          Another form of hypnotizer, in this col
          lection, is a large horshoe magnet with an
          attached armature. It is given to a sensi
          tive who is told to continuously separate
          and fit together the two parts. A similar
          magnetic hypnotizer is a steel ring to fit
          the index finger. The ring is of magnetized
          steel and is broken at one place, the space
          being filled by a small steel armature.
          These two contrivances are used princi
          pally for humoring the more unsophisti
          cated and superstitious sensitives who fos
          ter the belief that hypnotism is supernat
          ural. The magnet in most cases suggests
          mystery to the ignorant and sensitives of
          that class are readily excited by it. The
          ring device, also called a hypnoscope, Is
          used by some hypnotists for determining
          sensitives. Hypnotizable persons are al
          leged to experience certain tinglings in the
          skin and twitchings of the muscles while
          wearing it. A more complicated instru
          ment in this collection, which may be used
          as a hypnoscope, is a bulb-shaped rod, re
          sembling an electrode, which may be
          made to create pressure against the
          palm of the hand by a spring inside. When
          the pressure Is applied the subject is asked
          if he feels an electric shock. If he so con
          fesses he is rated as a hynotic sensitive.
          Sometimes the whole frame will tremble
          as a result of this imaginary electrical
          fluid.
          Crystal Viaions.
          Equally interesting devices of a related
          class, now growing in vogue among certain
          experimental hypnotists, are for applica
          tion to sensitives for the purpose of caus
          ing hallucinations known as crystal visions.
          One instrument of this class is a ball of
          crystal mounted upon a handle. Mirrors
          and other polished or transparent surfaces
          are employed for the same effect. The
          crystal or reflecting medium by producing
          partly obscured or scattered reflections to
          the sensitive mind's eye aid the subje-t
          in perceiving unnatural mental embodi
          ments of various objects. Many abnormal
          persons, habitually haunted by phantasms,
          for which visions they develop appetites,
          so to speak, employ these crystals and re
          flectors for throwing themselves into states
          during which they may experience what Is
          alleged to be the actual or imagined "sixth
          sense" or "second sight." Crystal gazing
          has lately become so popular that many
          psychic experimentalists in Europe are in
          viting tests with the paraphernalia thus
          employed, and agents were some time
          since engaged by the Society for Psychical
          Research to furnish balls for the purpose.
          Prof. Win. Romaine Newbold of the Uni
          versity 'of Pennsylvania recently made an
          extensive Investigation of crystal vision
          and found that twenty-two subjects out of
          eighty-six could perceive illusions by gaz
          ing into mirrors, surfaces of water- and
          objects of glass varying in form. Phan
          tasms appeared to the sensitives usually
          within five minutes, being prec~ed direct
          ly by cloudiness, hazes of color or illumin
          ations before the eyes. The phantasms
          varied from dim outlines to brilliant col
          ored pictures. Like dreams some of these
          forms were based upon recent experiences
          of the subjects, while others were purely
          fantastic.
          An Experiment.
          A simple experiment in thi\ line may be
          tried at home by any one who *11 sit before
          an open window, at twilight, keeping his
          gaze fixed preferably upon some landscape,
          distant row of houses or collection of con
          spicuous clouds. If the temptation to wink
          the eyelids can be resisted until the eyes
          become greatly fatigued, so as to remain
          open only at a great strain, the natural
          images will gradually grow more and more
          indistinct, and will apparently arrange
          themselves into fantastic groups or fade in
          to rapidly changing forms. The abnormal
          imagination of a person subject to Uight
          hallucinations would readily discern weird
          phantoms in such a picture.
          Drugs, such as urethane, suiphonal, peaa
          dehyde, etc., are now used successfully to
          produce a sleep which to all appearances is
          hypnotic. Some foreign hypnotists use
          ether and chloroform to induce hypnosis.
          Recent experiments indicate that there is
          a great similarity between hypnosis and theI
          action of hasheesh,as well as the newly test
          ed mescal, which is used by certain of our
          western Indians to produce trances. Phe
          nomena very similar to hypnosis is now
          noticed also during the ordinary sleep pro
          duced by simple anaesthetics, and the ques
          tion is being asked, Do anaesthetics produce
          hypnosis? A member of the Royal Chemi
          cal Society of London recently demonstrated
          that man possesses two distinct conscious
          nesses. He says that persons under the in
          fluence of anaesthetics. while not conscious
          of what is happening at the time of the
          operation, are sometimes able, several days
          after, to describe in detail what was hap
          pnnto e them. Wrhat he.n call t.."o
          Best Natural A
          25 Years' S.5
          Highest Reputation
          CAUTION: None genuine
          of the
          "Andreas E
          On the
          aday consciousnE as" was absent at the time.
          but the "subliminal consciousness." he says.
          was present during the operation. Hence
          anaesthetics destroy the former and only
          postpone the enregistering of the sensation
          conductors controlling the latter conscious
          ness. It may be that this "subliminal con
          sciousness" is the one affected by hypnot
          ists.
          Senlttve to Drmss.
          Recent laboratory experiments have also
          been made to ascertain the effects of drugs
          upon persons in a hypnotic state. Some
          subjects are found to be so sensitive to
          drugs while in this condition that they con
          tort themselves in various ways when the
          substances are not applied directly, but
          merely held in proximity to their skin, not
          even touching it. Some chemical substanc+-s,
          even when sealed in tubes, will cause sen
          sitives to alter their bodily appearances and
          physical conditions, producing violent con
          vulsions, hallucinations, alterations of the
          pupils, changes In the pulse-beats, symp
          toms of joy, grief or anger and other emo
          tional conditions.
          The influence of color upon hypnotized
          persons has also been tested in the labo
          ratcry by subjecting sensitives to rays of
          light passing through various screens of
          different colored glass. Blue light is found
          to produce sadness, red light joy, yellow
          light strong sffection and violet or green
          light variable conditions. Charcot used a
          sudden ray of Intense light as one means
          or throwing sensitives into the hypnotic
          state.
          Just as these instruments for producing
          hypnosis are applied to the sense of sight,
          other physical methods are applied, in its
          induction, to the senses of hearing and
          touch. The condition does not seem to be
          induced by stimulations of either taste smell. Charcot threw some of his subjects
          into hypnotic states by the sharp and
          sudden sounding of a large gong. The
          ticking of a watch has been used with
          the same success by others, the sensitive
          being required to concentrate his mind
          upon the sound. just as he does upon the
          seeing of the revolving fans or nickel ball.
          The monotonous chants sung by semi
          civilized nations are found to produce the
          same effect.
          Strokes and Passes.
          For creating hypnosis through the sense
          of touch, strokings or pressure upon the
          skin are resorted to by some hypnotists,
          while others apply warm plates of metal
          to different parts of the body. Physicians
          realize that warmth induces natural sleep,
          while coldness tends to prevent it. Some
          foreign hypnotists maintain that the crown
          of the head, roof of the nose, the thumb
          or elbow are most sensitive to hypnotic
          stimulation by touch. Some merely
          s'ratch the skin of the neck or touch the
          forehead. The electric battery has been
          resorted to by a few experimenters, who
          claim that it is successful. as an inducing
          agent. It is said to cause the same imag
          inary effect as the magnet.
          It is now an easy matter for certain hyp
          niotists to transform natural sleep into
          hypnotic sleep without the subject's knowl
          edge. Thus one .who gces to sleep in a
          public place may never remember what
          foolish actions he has been made to do
          Ouring that period. Hypnotic suggestion is
          the latest phase of this whole subject which
          is now interesting experimenters. A sensi
          tive, under hypnotic influence, receives a
          command fram the hypnotist which he
          will obey on awakening, altough he is un
          onsciou of ever having received such a
          ommand. This power is used by a physi
          cian in Massachusetts, who is said to be
          able to stop the most severe pain by sug
          gestion. Several people report to the Soci
          ety for Psychical Research that he has
          given thcm suggestions before they have
          gone to the dentist, %ith the result that
          their dentstry has invariably been painless,
          kxperiments are now being made as to the
          valu. of hypnotic suggestion in education.
          Its medical value has already neen proven
          in France. where such conditions as ner
          vous insomnia, sonambulism, kleptomania,
          ilziness and varicus forms of moral degen
          eracy have been cured by its means.
          Ues of Hypnosis.
          The power of suggestic n as an agent in
          crime is now being talked about in this
          country. Men are believed to have been
          banged for committing murder while acting
          under hypnotic Influence from another.
          Some celebrated medico-legalists have pro
          posed that laws should be passed defining
          the responsible murderers in such cases.
          In such an event hypnotism will be as both
          ersome a plea of defense as insanity is to
          day. The dangers threatened by the vicious
          or careless hypnotist have become legally
          realized In France and Russia. In the
          former hypnotism is forbidden for purposes
          of public amusement, and in the latter no
          persons except, licensed physicians can
          practice It It is said that tilt per cent of
          ithe people In thne world are hypnotizable.
          The hypnotists, on the other hand, are dis
          covering and improving their powers faster
          and faster each day. Will they at some
          future century become the governing class
          If a door is hung
          to swnmy one way,
          I there s no use
          trying to push it
          the other w ay.
          .1 There is a right
          and a wrong way
          to do things.
          Many thousands
          of women in
          and would like to
          be well. T he y
          aremaking efforts
          to get well, hut
          they are making them in the wrong way.
          They are taking medicines prepared by in
          competent nurses, or inexperienced physi
          cians. They ar alubmitting to exam
          inations and local treatment, for which thesem
          Is generally no necessity. They are grow
          ngsteadily worse instead of steadily better.
          Tere is no reason why almost every wo
          man should not be well and strong. Over
          thirty years ago, Dr. R. V. Pierce, of Buf
          falo, an eminent and successful specialist in
          the treatment of the diseases of women,
          discovered a wonderful specific for woman's
          diseases las since become world
          mous as .r Pirce's Favorite Prescription,
          It cures all forms of female weakness ad
          disease, Its effect is immediately ecpi
          ble in the better feeling of the palnit
          forces ont impuiy soothes e infianema
          tion that is always present in disorders of
          this kind, promotes regularity, and stops
          debilitating drains on the system. It cures
          nevuness, ritailty 19epe.mesa*, lac
          CREAT FiEDICAL. BOOK FREE.
          Every' womaan should have a coyof Dusder
          Pierce's Comamou Sense Medical Adviser. R ts
          a handosey illustrated wolusa
          of womnen. It is writtn a
          thre hnrd illsttissu
          colored plates. Untif recently,
          it was aoid at a dollar and a
          hafa ,and at tis price,
          of sia hundred and eighty thu
          sand copies. Rt Is now oareed,
          mlerba~d. bssistey fwa to any woman who
          to cove the o mail o Westd'
          dhbnding if ihdn is, a each
          thty ai in aleLm
          !orld's
          perient Water.
          cess in U. S.
          .A Over the Worm.
          without the signature
          firm
          axlehner,
          Label.
          es of the earth, and will the great host of
          sensitives become their slaves? Perhaps
          that is somewhat the case now. Trust
          worthy authorities relate hypnotism with
          the same power by which the teacher Im
          Presses his students, the preacher converts
          his congregation, the pleader convinces the
          jury, the cross-examiner "rattles" the wit
          new. or by which the orator holds his audi
          ence with bated breath. receiving cheers at
          every nod. although heard and understood
          by few. According to this. Mr. Bryan is a
          hypnottst. and doubtless Mr. McKinley is
          one. JOHN ELFRETH WATKINS. Jr.
          Grand Dukes and COetrews.
          A refreshing story is told In the columns
          of the Frankfort Gazette: The czar intrust
          ed Coint Pahlen, a liberal-minded man,
          with an inquiry into the causes of the ter
          rible disaster at Moseow on the occasion
          of the coronation, and the count did not
          hesitate to tell his majesty, in the presence
          of Grand Duke Vladimir. that he would
          have done better not to put the superin
          tendence of the coronation festivals into
          the hands of the grand duke. This frank
          declaration staggered the emperor. who
          asked Count Pahlen to advance his reasons.
          The count answered: "The grand dukes are
          in their right place in the army and navy.
          but If they have to do with purveyors and
          purveyance they must. be cheated." The
          Grand Duke Vladimir protested against
          this, but smilingly Count Pahlen reminded
          him of his own had experiences In conneo
          tion with the building of the memorial
          church to Alexander II. In consequence of
          this frank attitude of Count Pahlen. the
          minister of justice was ordered to continue
          the inquiry. He succeeded in clearing up
          the dark affair. but when the investigation
          bhgan to take a very disagreeable turn it
          was determined to submit it not to the or
          dinary court of justice. but to the minis
          terial council-in other words, to burke it.
          Gladness Comes
          W ith a better understanding of the
          transient nature of the many phys
          ical ills, which vanish before pro pr ef
          forts-gentle efforts-pleasant efforts
          rightly directed. There Is comfort in
          the knowledge, that so many forms ot
          sickness are not due to any actual dis
          ease, but simply to a constipated eondl
          tion of the system, which the pleasant
          family laxative, Syrup of Figs, prompt
          ly removes. That is why it is the only
          remedy with millionsof families, andzI
          everywhere esteemed so highly by all
          who value good health. Its beneficial
          effects are due to the fact, that it is the
          one remedy which promotes internal
          cleanliness without debilitating the
          organs on which it acts. It is therefome
          all important, in order to get its bene
          flhial effects, to note when you put
          chase, that you have the genuine arti
          cle, which is manufactured by the Cali
          fornia Fig Syrup Co. only and sold by
          all reputable druggists.
          If in the enjoyment of good health,
          and the system Is regular, laxatives or
          other remedies arc then not needed. If
          afflicted with any actual disease, one
          may be commended to the most skillful
          physicians, but if in need of a laxative,
          one should have the best, and with thme
          well-informed everywhere, Syu of
          Figs stands highest and Is mos largly
          used and gives most general satisfclm
          ROOFING.
          Improvements paented tses in the U. S.,
          Cana and Europe.
          PIEBPROOF-Proof against aparks, cinder%
          burning brands, etc.
          STONG -A heavy canvas foundation.
          LJGttT Weighs but 8s lbs. per rou sq. ft. whea
          laid complete.
          FLEXIBLm tontains no coal tar, snd retains
          indefinitecly its leather-like pliability and
          toughlness.
          P.ASiLY APPiaED -Requires no kettle nr nther
          expensive apparatus. Can be laid by
          any intelligent workman.
          Asestes Materials, LigaMiFaPalt, 3lman-Fige
          ad Beiler Ceverings, Steam PeerMegs etc.
          MJAJummaT nascan-r5 m sr0 wnSAUMn5S ses av man.
          H. W. JOHNS KFG. CO.,
          6r MAIDEN L.ANE, NEW YORK.
          09
          I20Z. Sock 10 Cents.
          *Ogoretle paper with5
          Zac o9 w ack.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1901-07-14/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=hypnosis+hypnotism</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>hypnotism to be part and
          parcel of medical practice?
          Judging from zt'hat some of
          the doctors say, it is so useful an
          aid to medicine that zve may expect
          to see it in the near future
          packed away hi every neatly mono
          grammed black leather case that
          accompanies a frock coat.
          Judging from what others of the
          doctors say, it is all one with
          quackery, with foolery, with fak-
          Dr. Q. J. Fitzgibbon.
          Dr. C. Kenz.
          Dr. C. C. Kenyon.
          Dr. F. "W. D'Evelyn.
          Dr. George F. Shiels.
          It is only the effort to reduce results to a scien
          tific causation that has attracted so much atten
          tion to the psychical condition of hypnosis. That
          this power should have not only a significance
          but utility is not an illogical conclusion, arid any
          Hypnotism will never take the place of
          an anesthetic. I have not taken much In
          terest in it because I do no»think It is of
          any' benefit' In therapeutics, except In
          cases of nervousness or hysteria. The
          immense amount of time it takes to treat
          by hypnotic influence is one thing against
          it, and its limitations are another.
          Dr. J. "W. Thorn.
          Hypnotism exists and has always done
          bo. It is coeval with man and the evolu
          tion of the higher animal forms, as l\ is
          rot either in its presence or phenomena
          eciely confined to the former. The weird
          influence of the Hindoo fakir o\'er the
          eerpent of the field, or in turn, the subtle
          fascination of the reptile over Its para
          lyzed prey, are in fact based upon the
          same principle as the experiments of a
          Paracelsus or a Charcot— viz., the elimina
          tion and concentration of a force or in
          fluence which pervades life, creating an
          atmosphere of reflexodism— as palpable as
          It is universal.
          ;It is! a 'very dangerous force, and I do
          net approve of its use cither by physicians
          or. any one else. When put to -legitimate
          purpose it Is not of any., great''"* benefit
          either, in medicine; or surgery.. It" could
          not possibly take the place of an-anes
          thetic, although It has been substituted
          for it in mild 'operations -where the pain
          would not, even were the .patient con
          scious, De very severe.
          [stsrlng Intently': at their reflection- In a
          i mirror. These cases surely are paralleled:
          ?by a large and not unfamiliar class,. who
          so persistently see "self ever-reflected
          self— that they finally, rest in the calm and
          peaceful- hypnosis that -amidst all- mun
          dane phenomena they are ever IT. Would
          it not be cruel to awake them?
          The use. of hypnotism Is riot a matter of
          indifference and demands the same -pre
          cautions as would be employed in the
          therapeusis of any potent agent. It is in
          teresting to. note a certain phase of auto-
          Infection— of a consolatory- and flattering
          'character— not'infrequently found in will
          ingly hypnotized patients, viz., a power to
          produce the hypnotic- state simply by
          ¦^-•y/v-T" r j,
          the; '"weak-minded", that are amenable;
          ¦on' theicontrary, .the mentally strong pro^
          vlded -they are -passive— often" afford the
          most profound 'results.-
          i Children iare of ten beneficially treated,
          not whichin children is apt to produce a feel
          •Ing 'of .awe j or fear, akin I to 'that begotten
          by. the; mention of a bogyman, but by con
          centration of the mind upon some phy
          sical "exercise which throws Into- activity
          the set bf organs— contrary to those eni-'
          ployed in produclpg the 1 morbid phe
          nomena.
          In true organic disease Its
          power would essentially be lim-
          Hed"to the modification of cer-.
          tain symptoms associated
          therewith, e. g.jhraln, sleepless
          ness," fear. All persons are not
          equally.; susceptible,- nor must
          it be concluded that it is "only
          Hypnotism has been success
          fully employed;as a '''/medicinal
          agent," but its field, probably
          for the reason above stated, Is
          at present limited.' If we should
          define a class of maladies, in
          which j it .has proved and will
          likely prove most valuable, we
          should say. It- will be- that of
          functional nervous diseases.' J
          f all should j probably be at
          tributed to. our faulty, interpre
          tation rather than to lack -of
          functional'activlty upon part of
          the force or bower.
          I have used hypnotism a great deal In
          my. practice, and yet I consider Its use
          very limited, almost entirely to nervous
          and hysterlcalpatlents, and I do not think
          it' possible for it to ever take the place
          of an anesthetic because of the length of
          time it requires, and also because some
          are not susceptible to its influence.' No
          one knows what type of person is the
          most susceptible, as opposites in charac
          teristics and temperament prove both sus
          ceptible and resistant. »I have used hyp
          notism on nearly, a hundred patients, but
          it only after all supplemented In a smaller
          degree medicine. \lt cannot touch organic
          trouble, and the length of time consumed
          in' hypnotizing a patient is a great draw
          back.; I do not thlnkthe morphine' habit
          can be cured by it; ,--C-'
          Dr. A. A. D'Ancona.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085187/1904-05-13/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=hypnosis+hypnotism+hypnotize+HYPNOTIZES</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>PROMINENT PHYSiGIANS'S QUEER
          DELUSION; HYPNOTIZES HIMSELF
          NEW YORK, May 13.—At his own re
          quest Dr. Paul H. Collins, of 408 Central
          Park Wept, is now undergoing treatment
          at Bellevue hospital tor the strangest
          malady, or whatever it might be called,
          ill.l the physician.* at that institution
          have ever had to (leal with.
          He believes that he can hypnotise him
          self.
          For long be hag delved into the im-!«iie.«
          of hypnotism, and it in believed that bis
          mind has become so imbued with the sub
          ject M to result in a moat singular im
          pairment.
          On other subjects the unfortunate physi
          cian it perfectly rational. Physically his
          condition in good. He seem* to realise
          that his self-hypnosis is a weird delusion,
          a nightmare of a disordered mind, but try
          as he will, so far he has been utterly un i
          able to rid himself of it.
          For a year it has haunted him night and
          day. "The end can only be death," he
          repeats pathetically. And Dr. Collins I
          dreads the very name of death, and, no j
          wonder, for he firmly believes that it will
          come to him in a ghastly manner.
          "I will gome day hypnotize myself." li« i
          tells the hospital physicians, "into a state
          of coma, and then be buried alive.'' This
          dread thought is with him ever.
          Dr. Parker, head of the psychopathic
          ward, is unable to state what will be the
          ultimate result of this strange case. The
          alienist does not believe self-hypnosis pos
          sible.
          To your correspondent he said: "There
          is do authenticated record of inch a thing.
          It i- ,c remarkable delusion, more remark
          able in the Fact that on oilier subject*
          Dr. Collins can converse sanely, even bril
          liantly. As for hit- intense fear of death
          any one would have that who carried con
          stantly with him the braln-rnking idea
          that his certain fate- was to "be buried
          alive."
          Other members of the medical profession
          ■who have known Dr. Collins in the past,
          state that he has been a great student, lias
          ample funds, and is of a liberal mind and
          generous disposition. He is a big man,
          aged somewhere in the titties, and has
          never married. His mother lives in the
          northern part of New York state. His
          brother is in Buffalo.
          When Dr. Collins went to the hospital
          he astonished Dr. Parker by exclaiming:
          "I am .1 doctor, like yourself, and I want
          you to thoroughly examine me and tell me
          whether I am going crazy."
          "What seems to be the trouble?" asked
          Dr. Parker.
          And then came the story that reminds
          one sonic of Jekyl and Hyde. Dr. Collins
          told how he had studied deeply into he
          art of hypnotism anil had attained remark
          able success in its practice. He went on:
          '•Finally came the time when I discov
          ered that I could sit alone and hypnotize
          myself. The sensation is indescribable
          "and decidedly uncomfortable, and 1 realize
          QjsS^ WISH</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1912-12-29/ed-1/?sp=45&amp;q=hypnosis+hypnot+hypnotic+Hypnotism+HYPNOTISM+hypnotism+hypnotized</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>INCREASED USE
          OF HYPNOTISM
          Dr. J. D. QuackenboG Tells of Its Great
          Value to Physicians and Its
          Help to Sufferers
          W
          HEN the police of London.
          England, forcihly chocked thu
          activities of fortune teller,
          crystal globe gazers and simi
          lar charlatans who prey on tho credulity
          of men and women, us was told in a recent
          cablegram to Tim SU.v their action had
          indirectly an important bearlni' on the i
          public health. As a result of tlieptittiiii;
          of tho swindlers out of business the fact
          has been brought prominently to public
          attention that not only has the value of
          hypnotism and the treatment of patients
          oy mental suggestion come to be better
          appreciated bul also thut many highly
          cpinlilicd physicians in Knglaud and oNo
          whero in Europe are making n specialty
          of psychic treatment. With the down
          fall of the charlatan fortune tellers and
          others of their typo who have sought to
          make illegitimate uso of hypnotism the
          number of reputable pructitioners who
          have adopted mental suggestion is grow
          ing. Certain physicians in the United States
          huve for borne time made u.e of mental
          suggestion or hypnotism in their practice
          and, the')' say, with distinct benefit to their
          patients, Dr. John D. Quackcnbo.s, who
          is n proiossor emeritus of Columbia Uni
          versity and who for a nutii'i' r o' "-a-has
          lectured on psychology in and outside
          of tho college, ha tused mental sii.-g t i 1
          on hypnotized persons, or sleeping sub
          jeels, as ho t -run them, moro than lo.'OO
          times nnd always, ho believes, with suo
          ci'is in tho casiM of tlicno s Pfe.-ing f-om
          physical as well as from nuntal diso.m.
          "Very much interest hr.s been ere.. tod
          ln.r.t i'u 11 t-itunlt iT 'l'lll. Kl.v'a f t.tn.im-n
          'r., i., ,f .1... ,.'...i. i... f ,i,
          lolico there ,.g. Inst dlshon.'st users of outrols the congestion, hyper-secretion,
          hypnotism end ly the. elded statemet t f"1'1:'"4 "r ",0 H-ad und asihina.
          that there is evidence, of 1111 iniTei-sed -.Slamtiiering unci other hjieech defects
          use of mental sugrostion by physicians appropriate conditions for treat mem
          in England and in the Continent," s..id!''' l'ymotis.n. while pulhologieul bush
          Dr. (JuackenU.s. 'This was emlv to bo f "ess or morbid Milf-consciotisness.
          e'xpocii'el. for tho value of such treatment
          h .si eonelemonstratedbv such tihvsl I l.s
          of worldwide reputition rs Pr. I.loyd-
          Tuckey and Pr. MllnoHramwoll of London,
          who are using this instniino:it.;llty to
          re-scuo the sick nnd mentally do.iresseel
          with marked suce'essj Dr. l area a'.el Dr.
          Iicrillon in Paris, vim h vo a school of
          psychology, where public) trc-.tmont is
          dally given; Dr. (Srossm n of llerlln,
          who Ronio time npo ctte:.ilesl the C.irlna
          of 1'ussi.i, giving her psychio troatmer.t;
          Prof. Froel in .ttrieh if.d Prof. Paul
          Dubois r.t Porno, Swltzer'and; Dr. vort
          Velscn nt Brussels, Itelgium; Dr. von
          .Schrcnolc-Notzliig ut Munich, Germ my
          and Dr. von nontorghoi aid Dr. van
          Ecdcn at Amsterdam. Hollmd, all of
          them using mental suggestion li 0110
          form or another. In tho United St ;tcs
          such treatment is constantly Increaslni;.
          "As a mutter of fact the greatest value
          of psychio treatment is in cases of neuras
          thenia, delusions and Imperative con
          ceptions which are largely dependent on
          chemical conditions which lire remediable.
          No dNeuse is purely mental or purely
          physle-il. The advanced physician not
          only offers specillo tre it merit to thes
          subjects but rights tho chemistry o'
          the body by removing tho ititostina
          poisoning that in so markedly responsibh
          for the.e delusions.
          I "Hypnotism is specUlly applicable t
          j the cure of phobias oi fair, such .s tin
          fear of lightning, dust, crowds, solitude
          klhe fe.ir of responsibility, ilNo-so, of
          becoming deformed, of blushing; tlio fair
          of sleeple-sness; tho fear of dogsor rabies,
          to s. y nothing of continual impulses to
          strike mine one, to strangle children,
          or to commit other crimes which r.re ex
          pressions of true psychaMhenia or mental
          e.xli uistion.
          "It Is a peculiar thing that sometimes
          people with the best intentions in the
          world will often bo huuntcd by impera
          tive impulses to lnjtir their neighbors
          or even their own children. Theso im
          putes aro as a rule controlled, but seem
          simply to torture the subject. They de
          pend on an exhaustion of tho nervous
          substance in tho brain cells from over
          work, worry or shock.
          "An an illustration, I had a patient who
          wIi-mi business became unusually active,
          111 for instance just before the holidays,
          was seized witli nil impulse to take ti
          hatchet anil I. ill some one. This ImpuUe
          was so great that he was induced to koep
          away from hatchets, clubs or similai
          implements with which he might do harm
          were they in his sight.
          "There is i distinct elifferenco betweer
          this cnndlMon and tho homicidal impulse
          of an insane person, for tho neurasthenic
          will never do harm when observed, while
          the insane person is liliel.' to carry out
          his homicidal Impulse at any time. Il
          is in such cases that mental suggestion
          affords the only relief.
          "Psychio suggestion lias boon largely
          employed in the treatment of e-pilopsy.
          Ilystero-i.pile.psy, the hysterical counter
          feit or epilepsy, is absolutely curable In my
          experience.
          "Another elisease that yields to meiitul
          suggestion supplemented by regular
          treatment l.s diabetes. Tho patient under
          hypnosis is urged to correct the perverted
          nervous function, ho that first tlmsturchy
          matter constinnsl as food shall bo prop
          erly assimilated and second that sugar
          shall not bo manufactured in tlio body
          to excess. Mental simci-stioiis uro nddod
          I to counteract the appetite for swei'ts nnd
          eNccsslve thirst. All my patients have
          I been markedly beiirliteel or cut irely cured
          I by hypnotic! treatment, which I now give
          n connection w ith the llulgariati bacillus.
          1 In my last case of this treatment the
          sugar dropped from ll'4 lot) per cent.
          I "The lliilgarian bacillus, it may be
          explained, is thu enemy of tho bacteriu
          that produco putrefaction in tho intes
          tines, and that are regiiided is one
          cause of diabetes. It is so named becutisi
          in llulguria S,h u persons huo been fuimi
          who were more than 100 years of age
          and who were still healthy and active
          Investigation showed that their longevit;
          was duo to tlie fact that they lived largol.
          oil sour milk products, i hereforo th'
          1 liaracterNlio bacillus of tho sour mil.
          has been naturally termed the llulgariai
          bacillus. In all cases or diabetes remark
          able gains in energy have followe el th.
          early treatments by psychics suggestion
          I "In buy fever, again, mental suggestion
          Idoatroys he irritability or tho nasn
          mucous membrane, lis sensibility te
          Irrl.uting substuuees in tho atmosphere
          I t"o way. is extremely common
          nmoli'? public speukcrs. singers, actors
          and even business men und women, is
          readily cured by upproprinto mental
          suggestion. In tho treatment of such
          cases tho sleeping nubject or tho person
          under hypnosis must bo. imbued with a
          feeling of equality, and all unso of in
          feriority in tho presence of his follow
          beings removed, lie le inudo to seo that
          tho undervaluation or pulf is immoral
          I localise It Billitraets irom 111s oiuciciicy
          or capacity for happluess.
          ".Mental suggestion, or hypnotUm,
          whichever phrase you prefer, properly
          administered upiN to tho God part
          of tlio person under treat tnimt. That is
          tho truth, and thnt, ipilto likoly, is tho
          necret of its grout v.iluo anil omcaoy
          This lelng so there can Im no ground for
          objection to nor criticism of its uso hi
          healing the sick. It Is an advanced stop
          in tho proctico of tnediolno, and whatever
          benefits suffering mankind must In all
          justice be welcomed."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86053696/1892-11-18/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=abuse+of+hypnotism</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>the abuse of hypnotism.
          Quacks anil Chui-lutans Who Mab« Um of
          II to Gall the Public.
          While the benefits from hypnotism
          thus far have been few and small, the
          evila have been many and great. Ita
          aleeplike state ia not a normal sleep,
          bringing health and strength to the
          ilnmberer, but a morbid condition bor
          dering upon disease. It irritates the en
          tire nervous organization and tempora
          rily if not organically weakens the sys
          tem. This drawback is serious enough.
          Darker and more terrible effects lie in
          the suppression Of the object's will for
          the time being, and the substitution
          therefor of the operator's. Iu this re
          gard it opens avenues to crime and crimi
          nals such us has never been equaled
          heretofore. Already so many discredit
          able actions, not to use a stronger word,
          have been committed in Europe by
          means of hypnotism that in Italy, Aus
          tro-Hungary, parts of Switzerland, Co
          penhagen and other municipalities laws
          have been unacted prohibiting its public
          practice by any except physicians. So,
          on the other hand, the police, without
          any statute on the subject, have treated
          traveling mesmerists as disorderly char
          acters. Thus Donato was expelled from
          Italy, and Hansen, another hypnotist,
          from Austria, was notified never to re
          turn under penalty of arrest, fine and
          imprisonment.
          This Donato (whose roal name, by the
          way, is Dhont) hypnotized an Italian ar
          tillery officer, who immediately became
          half crazy. From time to time he would
          go into somnambulism at the sight of a
          bright object. He would follow carriage
          lamps, and unless prevented would walk
          toward locomotive or steamer lights.
          An architectural student was mesmer
          ized by staring at his compasses, after
          which it was impossible for him to draw
          without going to sleep.
          A young girl of Milan, of beauty and
          character, was hypnotized aud impressed
          with the uotiou that she was married to
          a man she had uever seen but once, aud
          then in the darkness. She went crazy
          and died iu a hospital.
          Another young girl (of Paris, this
          time) was put under a similar spell aud
          wus ruined. She finally entered the
          baltpetrieru hospital, where, after a long
          aud puiuful remedy, what was left of
          her former self was pronounced cured.
          Iu New York a hypnotized person was
          made to believe that he had taken slow
          poison. He fell sick and wasted away
          to a shadow. Not until the attending
          physician discovered the true nature of
          the hallucination and rehypnotized the
          subject was there any symptom of con
          valescence.
          iu Turin, at a series of hypnotic lec
          tures and public experiments, a large
          proportion of those who attended were
          taken sick with headache, insomnia aud
          other nervous ailuieuts. A few of those
          who were of a hysterical temperament
          remained ill for a long time.
          In the foregoing cases the hypnotizing
          was done with no evil intent, but thero
          are hundreds of recorded instances where
          it was done with iuteut of evil.—Phila
          delphia Times.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016014/1896-10-29/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=abuse+of+hypnotism</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1908-07-05/ed-1/?sp=40&amp;q=abuse+of+hypnotism</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1908-07-05/ed-1/?sp=40&amp;q=abuse+of+hypnotism</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82015485/1908-03-21/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=abuse+of+hypnotism</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>